<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sessions on ApacheCon at Home 2021</title>
    <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions.html</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sessions on ApacheCon at Home 2021</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Apache httpd and TLS/SSL certificates validation</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1136.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1136.html</guid>
      <description>We will look to 2 different things here, validation of the server certificate andnvalidation of the client certificates. For the server certificate we will show Let&amp;rsquo;s encrypt and mod_md and speak aboutnthe new ACMEv2 protocol and OCSP stapling. For the client certificates we look to OCSP and other validations. Demo and quick start example will provided during the talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building an open source analytics distribution on Kubernetes that meets the needs of a modern data scientist.</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1146.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1146.html</guid>
      <description>Modern machine learning libraries such as Jupyter, Kubeflow, PyTorch on technologies that are managed outside of the linux foundation, often forcing users to pay for cloud or hosted offerings to manage integration and tool dependencys. This challenges the ability of the ASF to continue blazing a trail of open innovation in the data science and analytics frontiers which are transforming so many businesses today. New projects in the ASF: such as Airflow, PredictionIO, SystemML, and NiFi - combined with technologies such as Spark and HDFS can be used to build an end-to-end analytics solution that is flexible and modular enough to meet the needs of modern data scientists, at pedabyte scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Zhaopin&#39;s enterprise event bus based on Apache Pulsar</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1189.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1189.html</guid>
      <description>Zhaopin.com is a Chinese online recruitment services provider. As a bilingual job board, Zhaopin.com has one of the largest selections of real-time job vacancies in China. All recruitment advertisements are provided by prominent Chinese and foreign companies and enterprises throughout China. Zhaopin.com provides professional HR services to over 2.2 million clients and its average daily page views are over 68 million.nApache Pulsar was developed to address several shortcomings of existing messaging systems including a lot of enterprise features, message durability, and lower message latency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra Traffic Management at Instagram</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1042.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1042.html</guid>
      <description>Cassandra has been deployed for many years at Instagram and is still growing fast. Over the years, we’ve constantly improved the design of our infrastructure: we’ve introduced Cassandra proxy nodes to decouple the processing and storage workloads, we&amp;rsquo;ve developed Rocksandra, a new storage engine relying on RocksDB that reduced the GC pressure and improved the efficiency of our clusters. Lately, we&amp;rsquo;ve added an intermediate layer in our Cassandra infrastructure, where we could add many traffic optimizations to further improve our Cassandra clusters&#39; efficiency and reliability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Stream Data Pipeline on Google Cloud Platform using Apache Beam</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1322.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1322.html</guid>
      <description>We built a scalable and flexible stream data pipeline for our microservices on Google Cloud Platform (GCP), using Cloud Pub/Sub, Google Cloud Storage, BigQuery, and Cloud Dataflow, using Apache Beam. The stream data pipeline is working on the production system for Mercari, one of the biggest C2C e-commerce services in Japan. The pipeline currently accepts logs from 5+ microservices, and the number will increase soon. Our microservice architecture is based on the following three concepts:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Movement &amp; Integration at PayPal &amp; LinkedIn using Apache Gobblin</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1149.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1149.html</guid>
      <description>Data replication at PayPal drives various different business use-cases from fraud detection, user behavioral analysis, credit checks to lot of other offline business decisions. During this talk, we will present how Apache Gobblin empowers data movement and integrations at PayPal in partnership with LinkedIn to showcase all the recent features as well as the planned roadmap for the platform. Apache Gobblin is a distributed data integration framework that simplifies common aspects of big data integration such as data ingestion, replication, organization and lifecycle management for both streaming and batch data ecosystems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Production-ready stream data pipeline in Merpay, Inc</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1329.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1329.html</guid>
      <description>We’ve started to provide our stream based data pipeline by using Google Cloud Dataflow and Apache Beam since 2018 fall. It collects event logs from microservices running on GKE, then transforms and forwards the logs to GCS and BigQuery to use for analytics, etc. As you know, implementing and operating streaming jobs are challenging. We’re encountered various issues during that time. I’d like to share our knowledge on development and operation perspective.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Recent advances in Natural Language Processing and Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1119.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1119.html</guid>
      <description>In recent years, Machine Learning (ML) approaches to Natural Language Processing (NLP) drastically changed. From a feature-based modelling, where NLP tasks are tackled by using a set of manually engineered features, we moved to the so-called representation learning: text is naturally represented as a sequence of symbols (e.g., words, characters, etc.) and the role of learning how these symbols should be represented is entirely left to the ML method. Deep Learning dominates such paradigmatic shift.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tips and Tricks - Getting the most out of Apache Cordova</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1207.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1207.html</guid>
      <description>Mobile development is hard, no matter what tools you use. With thenmultitude of devices out there how can you maximize the chance to delightnyour users? Jesse has been actively contributing to hybrid mobilendevelopment projects and writing hybrid mobile apps for 10 years and willnshare his bag of tricks. Learn best practices so you can optimize yournworkflow, and develop the best possible mobile applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Widening the Circle: The open source journey from user to contributor</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1116.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1116.html</guid>
      <description>Open source draws its strength from the communities that use and build it. It&amp;rsquo;s their diversity of perspective, skills, and accountability that makes individual projects stronger and builds a richer and solid ecosystem. But while open source is used by the entire world, that broad user community is not yet reflected in the contributor base. In fact, diversity in open source is significantly worse than in proprietary software. While we claim that contribution is open to all, clearly not everybody feels empowered or welcome to contribute to open source projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Beginner&#39;s Guide to HTTPS and TLS</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1091.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1091.html</guid>
      <description>This talk will introduce you to the fundamentals of securing communications with HTTPS. We will start by explaining the basics of X.509 server and client certificates, certification authorities, and using the OpenSSL toolkit. The TLS/SSL protocol will be introduced and how it is used together with HTTP in order to provide for data encryption, integrity, and authentication. We will talk through some important configuration details, standard use cases, common pitfalls, known SSL vulnerabilities, and issues when using HTTPS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra 4.0: Our Most Stable Major Release</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1095.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1095.html</guid>
      <description>In mid-2018 the Cassandra community committed to making Cassandra 4.0 the most stable major release of Cassandra in the project’s history. In September, the community shifted focus from feature work and development to ensuring the quality of the release. To this end, we have adopted several new approaches to testing and validation including the replaying of production traffic, code audits, and property-based testing. This talk will explore the methodologies we’ve adopted and the results of their application as well as costs of this level of commitment to testing and its benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Creating Custom Streaming Events to Learn Apache Beam</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1328.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1328.html</guid>
      <description>Learning a streaming framework like Apache Beam is exciting but with &amp;lsquo;Hello World!&amp;rsquo; examples aren&amp;rsquo;t fun. There aren&amp;rsquo;t a lot of free and interesting streaming data sources for beginners to play with, it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to give up learning if it&amp;rsquo;s boring. To keep myself learning something new, I find myself need incentives and accomplishments to continue. If you are like me need some motivation to keep learning, this talk will give you some inspiration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer segmentation and personalization in websites/PWAs using Apache Unomi</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1210.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1210.html</guid>
      <description>In this session, you will learn all that’s new with Apache Unomi, the open source Customer Data platform (that graduated this year) based on the Apache Karaf runtime, and all that’s happened since the last ApacheCon. You will discover how to easily integrate it with an existing website or SPA/PWA using its built-in web tracker, how to build customer segments and how to use the API to personalize the experience for your users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Event Sourcing with Spring Boot and Apache Kafka</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1194.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1194.html</guid>
      <description>In our global economy, businesses must be nimble and often have to adapt quickly. As a result, many businesses structure their teams in an Agile way to keep up with this demand. With Domain Driven Design, it’s possible to quickly modify applications to accommodate changing business needs and easily integrate with disparate third-party systems. But what if you were able to use historical data and analytics to enhance your applications capabilities?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OpenWhisk and Kubernetes based Mobile Backend as a Service</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1206.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1206.html</guid>
      <description>So you&amp;rsquo;ve been hearing a lot of buzz about Serverless tech in conjunction with Containers and Mobile, but what exactly is the OpenWhisk in reference to Kubernetes? Come find out at this session. Serverless has become the new style of coding, and it might be perfect to offload your mobile apps, and container based systems without incurring unnecessary costs.nGet an intro into serverless/function-as-a-service/cloud native technologies in the Mobile-Backend-as-a-Service (MBaaS) context and learn why startups and enterprises are so excited about using it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Riding Camel in Huawei Cloud</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1130.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1130.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Camel provides a powerful EIP (Enterprise Integration Patterns) DSL to integrate tons of different middlewares. Now more and more enterprise user moving their application into cloud, it could be a challenge for them to bridge the public cloud service and the inhouse build application from scratch. With the help of Apache Camel, we provide an integration services on Huawei Cloud to address this across cloud integration issues and extend integration ability by leveraging the community collaboration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Robust Elastic Scaling of Deep Learning on Kubernates</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1088.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1088.html</guid>
      <description>With the increasing popularity of deep learning workloads in academia, government and industry, several organizations have developed cloud-based deep learning platforms whose goals are to enable organizations utilize expensive resources effectively, and to share said resources among multiple teams in a fair and effective manner. We present the elastic scaling in the context of such large scale deep learning platforms. The traditional deep learning workload is the parallel job where can not fully utilize the cluster gpu resources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running an Apache Project: 10 Traps and How to Avoid Them</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1067.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1067.html</guid>
      <description>When you are starting on your open source adventure, there are lot ofnthings to learn that have very little to do with coding and insteadnrelate to interacting with people. Apache is, at its best, a group ofnpeople who are trying to share their experience and teach new projectsnand contributors how to successfully manage open source projects.nHowever, like the blind people each describing a part of an elephant,neach mentor brings their personal experience to the table, and thusncan give good, yet conflicting advice to new projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samza Portable Runner for Beam</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1321.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1321.html</guid>
      <description>In this talk we are going to cover how we have leveraged portability of Beam and make Stream Processing in Python possible on top of Apache Samza. We will first touch points on Apache Samza in general, and how it stands out as the stream processing engine at LinkedIn that scales to over a trillion messages processed per day, with strong state support and flexible deployment models. Next we introduce Samza Runner for Beam, particularly the portable runner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s New and Coming to Apache Hivemall: Building More Flexible Machine Learning Solution for Apache Hive and Spark</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1158.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1158.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Hivemall is a scalable machine learning library for Apache Hive, Spark, and Pig. Hivemall allows us to apply a wealth of machine learning techniques to massive data stored in distributed storage by just writing a series of SQL-like queries. It provides classification, regression, recommendation, anomaly detection, and topic modeling functionalities in a scalable manner, along with a variety of auxiliary functions for data preprocessing and feature engineering. This talk demonstrates the Hivemall library with a special emphasis on its new features merged after the first Apache Incubator release.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding AI to customer segmentation using Apache Unomi and Apache PredictionIO</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1086.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1086.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Unomi is a Customer Data Platform that is easy to extend as it uses the Apache Karaf runtime. In this session, you will discover how to integrate Unomi with Apache PredictionIO to be able to leverage artificial intelligence algorithms to recommend segments or products to users as they interact with websites. Of course, as all of this will be bleeding-edge stuff, expect plenty of last-minute drama, half-finished code and hopefully some fun demos.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Cassandra Sidecar, let’s make C* attractive and easy to operate</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1054.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1054.html</guid>
      <description>Cloud database offerings have expanded over the past decade, encompassing everything from virtualized machines in the cloud to entirely serverless databases. With this pace of innovation in the cloud ecosystem, Cassandra stands in a unique position to serve its users with unique advantages over any other system. This also puts Cassandra in an interesting position to compete with the ongoing innovations in the cloud. With the internal architecture and storage mechanism aside, citizen developers in the community are looking for several other operability aspects/ ecosystem around the services for the long term investments and benefits from such service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Training, How it came to be and what it is about</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1043.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1043.html</guid>
      <description>There are lots of companies offering training for, and around, the Apache ecosystem, as well as many other topics that all create their own training material. Keeping this material up to date, especially in the fast-moving open-source world is not an easy task and takes a lot of time and effort. And all the time someone not too far away is probably working on a very similar slide-deck to explain what ZooKeeper does&amp;hellip; It is this fundamental issue that the Apache Training project was created to address - centralising training resources and making them easier to access and (re-)use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Configuring Apache Camel for the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1111.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1111.html</guid>
      <description>Cloud … check. Container … check. Orchestration … check. Now that you’ve got the basics it’s time to starting thinking about how all occupants of your new cloud infrastructure are going to communicate. And no mater what cloud, container or orchestration tool you choose, Apache Camel has what you need to get your system configured and connected. This talk will cover Camel components for cloud friendly configuration, communication, packaging, and deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Everything about Apache Marvin Platform</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1082.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1082.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Marvin is an open source project that focuses on empowering data science teams to deliver industrial-grade applications supported by a high-scale, low-latency, language agnostic, and standardized architecture platform created to simplify the process of exploration and modeling in Machine Learning projects. Marvin aims at abstracting the complexities in the creation process of scalable, highly available, interoperable and maintainable predictive software. In this presentation, the speaker is going to talk about the architecture behind the platform and show the cooler features of Apache Marvin.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reverse Proxy Magic with Apache httpd 2.4</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1073.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1073.html</guid>
      <description>One of the best not-so-well-known features of Apache httpd is its incredible capability as a Reverse Proxy server. Whether as a front end to application servers such as Tomcat and PMP-FPM, or as a caching server for static content, or as a robust load-balancer with dynamic configuration, or all, Apache httpd is not only feature rich but easily matches or surpasses the performance of other proxies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless Event Streaming with Pulsar Function: Use Cases and Best Practices</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1193.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1193.html</guid>
      <description>As data continues to evolve, there are more and more requirements for calculating data. From servers to VMS to containers to serverless, the computing framework is constantly evolving with the needs of users. How to provide users with a fast, easy-to-deploy computing framework has become a question for everyone to think about. In this talk, we will introduce how Pulsar provides a powerful computing power based on the serverless computing architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serverless: Multi-tenant Rule Engine Service Powered by Apache Karaf</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1209.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1209.html</guid>
      <description>The Netflix media pipeline processes thousands of new shows and movies every day so that you can watch them on any device anywhere. We use a forward chaining rule engine to coordinate all of this work in multiple workflows. Hosting these workflows in a reliable, scalable and cost effective manner is a huge challenge at our scale. In this talk, we will introduce the design of Netflix’s next generation rule engine framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Power of Plugins -  Developing plugins for Apache Cordova</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1205.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1205.html</guid>
      <description>Plugins are the powerhouse inside Apache Cordova applications, this isnwhere all native functionality is exposed, and your mobile app trulynbecomes hybrid. We will explore the full scope of plugins in ApachenCordova, not just how they work, but how they are created, installed,ndiscovered and distributed. We will deep dive into concrete examples tondemonstrate the power of plugins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unifying Batch and Stream Data Processing with Apache Calcite and Apache Beam</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1320.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1320.html</guid>
      <description>At LinkedIn, we have a large and ever-expanding corpus of big data processing code written using batch processing frameworks like Pig, Hive, and Spark. These data processing pipelines produce derived data artifacts like metrics, dimensions, and features and are generally run at daily or hourly end-to-end latencies. For a subset of these artifacts, there often arises a need to produce them at a faster cadence, say minutely or even continuously. At that point, the common practice used to be that the developer would re-write the same derivation logic using a stream processing framework (Apache Samza in case of LinkedIn).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Writing the Hazelcast Jet Runner</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1327.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1327.html</guid>
      <description>Hazelcast Jet is a distributed data processing engine that threats all data as a stream. Jet is built on top of Hazelcast IMDG and thanks to this the Jet cluster can also play the role of the data source and sink. If you use Jet this way, you can achieve perfect data locality and top-of- the-class throughputs. Jet uses cooperative multithreading (comparable to green threads), it&amp;rsquo;s processors correspond to standalone single-threaded tasks that process streams of data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Agile Integration - Cloud Native Application Development</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1055.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1055.html</guid>
      <description>Cloud native application development is more than just container orchestration, when it comes to designing proper agile software architecture, there are many aspect that need to be taken into account. From simple microservices runtime, orchestration of core business, interacting with legacy, connecting with external SaaS application. To a more reactive system with events driven backbone, and also avoid data silos and how to deal with routing, versioning deployment strategy. Putting everything into a big picture, guide you through what next generation of cloud native architecture should be like and how everything works together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Beam &#43; Kotlin = ❤️ </title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1319.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1319.html</guid>
      <description>Kotlin is an Open Sourced, statically typed language for JVM and is mostly being favoured by Android Developers due to the many myriad features which enable more concise and cleaner code than Java without sacrificing performance or safety. By using Kotlin as our language of choice to build an apache beam pipeline, our development team not only ran into fewer errors than what we would have if we used Java; but with the help of extensively useful high level APIs present in Kotlin, we were also able to cut down on the development time required to build, test and deploy a new feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Fineract CN Mobile 2.0 - Supporting Branchless banking and promoting financial inclusion in the fragile states</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1204.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1204.html</guid>
      <description>In today&amp;rsquo;s world, we don&amp;rsquo;t have an offline first open source mobile banking solution. Nowadays It is too important to have an offline first application because in many rural areas, it is exceptionally hard to find an internet connection, sometimes taking days to get connected if a natural disaster happens Still, there are some areas where internet connection is still not even present and despite the many global efforts to bring connectivity forward, there are regions where there is still no timeline for connectivity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache httpd 2.4 Overview</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1057.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1057.html</guid>
      <description>All the Ins and Outs related to what&amp;rsquo;s old, and NEW, in Apache httpd 2.4. If you haven&amp;rsquo;t use httpd in awhile, this is a great way to find out all the new features and enhancements. And if you are a current user, you find out about how to tune httpd for peak performance</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Karaf on cloud, the kloud initiative</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1208.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1208.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Karaf has been seen for a while as an applications server. If it&amp;rsquo;s actually the case for the standard distribution, it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to create a Karaf powered standard/immutable distribution embedding your applications. In combination with other Karaf subprojects (Decanter, Cave, &amp;hellip;), it provides a perfect applications runtime for the cloud.nThis talk will show how to start and focus on business code and then generate different distribution packages, up to a docker image ready to run on cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From an idea to an Apache TLP</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1133.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1133.html</guid>
      <description>About 3 years ago, I had an idea of using Open-Source software to create the next generation of industrial it solutions. At ApacheCon 2017 in Miami I introduced this idea to the public with my &amp;lsquo;Building SCADA systems with Apache Software&amp;rsquo;. 2019 the Apache PLC4X project is an Apache TLP. In this talk I will not talk about technical details of the project itself, but all the steps we took on this journey from a community-building point of view.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hadoop Submarine Ecosystem: Bringing Machine Learning and Big Data world (YARN and Kubernetes) together </title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1196.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1196.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Data Scientists focuses on developing ML models with applications such as TensorFlow / MXNet / Caffe / XGBoost and do not deep dive into the complexities of computing and storage to run ML/DL jobs. Today’s most of ETL processed data are stored in HDFS and cloud, and leveraging this data to design strong ML models is a big challenge for a data scientist. In Big Data ecosystem, most of the ETL and batch jobs are running on Spark and Hive which process/ingest data to the same data stores.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interactive querying of streams using Apache Pulsar</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1192.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1192.html</guid>
      <description>As applications become more reliant on real-time data, streaming/messaging platforms have become more and more popular and crucial to any data pipeline. Currently, many streaming/messaging platforms are only used to access the most recent events from streams of data, however, there is tremendous value that can be unlocked if the full history of streams can be queried in an interactive fashion. Pulsar SQL is a query layer built on top of Apache Pulsar (a next-gen messaging platform), that enables users to dynamically query all streams, old and new, stored inside of Pulsar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pricing Lyft rides with Apache Beam - a case study in migrating from a worker-based workflow to streaming</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1326.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1326.html</guid>
      <description>Ride-sharing is a two-sided marketplace; balancing supply and demand with price in real time is critical to maintaining an efficient system. Dynamic pricing creates fairness for drivers (by raising rates when there is a lot of demand) and maintains good experiences for passengers (by satisfying pick-up time SLAs). This complex system makes real-time decisions using various data sources; machine learning models; and a streaming infrastructure for low latency, reliability and scalability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reduce your Storage Costs with Transient Replication and Cheap Quorums</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1188.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1188.html</guid>
      <description>nIn eventually consistent systems, when a node failures or network partition occurs, we’re presented with a trade-off: to execute a request and sacrifice consistency or reject execution and sacrifice availability. In such system, quorums, overlapping node subsets guaranteeing at least one node to hold the most recent value, can be a good middle-ground. We can tolerate failures and loss of connectivity for some nodes while still serving latest results. Quorum-based replication schemes incur high storage costs: we have to store redundant values on several nodes to guarantee enough copies are going to be available in case of failure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Guided Walkthrough of the Apache Beam Go SDK</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1318.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1318.html</guid>
      <description>This session will walk through the internals of what the Go SDK does to execute a pipeline. Describing the structure of the SDK, where code is located, and the why of the structure, and how it does it with the particular features of the Go language, which notably has strict types but no generics. Particular effort will be spent on what the Go SDK does for ease of use, and to reduce DoFn execution overhead.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advanced Apache Cordova Development</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1203.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1203.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Cordova is a platform for building mobile apps using common Web technologies (HTML, CSS and JavaScript). Apache Cordova offers a set of APIs that allow the mobile app developers to utilize mobile native functions such as (Audio, Camera, Contacts …etc) using JavaScript. This session discusses and demonstrates the advanced aspects of Apache Cordova. Advanced aspects include extending Apache Cordova framework by creating custom plugins in order to access more device hardware features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Groovy Update and Roadmap</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1033.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1033.html</guid>
      <description>This talk looks at the latest features in Groovy from 2.5 and 3.0. This includes new AST transforms, new macro features, the new Parrot parser and a myriad of other new miscellaneous features. The talk outlines a broad roadmap of how the new features are planned to be rolled out and the system requirements for each version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beaming Deep Learning with Ludwig</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1325.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1325.html</guid>
      <description>Ludwig is a code-free Deep Learning toolbox based on TensorFlow open-sourced by Uber AI Labs. Ludwig is unique in its ability to help make deep learning easier to understand for non-experts and enable faster model improvement iteration cycles for experienced machine learning developers and researchers alike. By using Ludwig, experts and researchers can simplify the prototyping process and streamline data processing so that they can focus on developing deep learning architectures rather than data wrangling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conquering Networked Applications using Ballerina Programming Language</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1103.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1103.html</guid>
      <description>Ballerina is the next generation programming language, which redefined what means to be &amp;lsquo;general purpose&amp;rsquo;. Historically, programming languages concentrated on single machine execution, in a controlled environment, and also for good reason, because any other external interactions were out of the scope of a programming language, at least in the bygone days that is. But now, the communication network is something that is always there, and software often doesn&amp;rsquo;t work alone.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kafka, Cassandra and Kubernetes at Scale - Real-time Anomaly detection on 19 billion events a day</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1187.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1187.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Kafka, Apache Cassandra and Kubernetes are open source big data technologies enabling applications and business operations to scale massively and rapidly. While Kafka and Cassandra underpins the data layer of the stack providing capability to stream, disseminate, store and retrieve data at very low latency, Kubernetes is a container orchestration technology that helps in automated application deployment and scaling of application clusters. In this presentation, we will reveal how we architected a massive scale deployment of a streaming data pipeline with Kafka and Cassandra to cater to an example Anomaly detection application running on a Kubernetes cluster and generating and processing massive amount of events.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One SQL to Rule Them All – a Syntactically Idiomatic Approach to Management of Streams and Tables</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1191.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1191.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Calcite is a data management framework that includes a SQL parser and query optimizer. It is used by many projects that implement SQL processing capabilities, including Apache Beam and Apache Flink. Over the last years, members of these three communities had many discussions about the semantics and syntax of &amp;lsquo;Streaming SQL&amp;rsquo;. End of last year, we decided to formalize and summarize our views and ideas in paper that we submitted to the Industrial Track of the SIGMOD 2019 conference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Apache Way May Save Us All</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1041.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1041.html</guid>
      <description>The commercial software industry is plagued by numerous significant problems: Cost and schedule overruns, poor software quality, unrealistic expectations, products that fail to meet customer needs, and more. These problems are historic, chronic, and pervasive; they’ve been with us for decades, and changes to methodology haven’t had much effect in remedying them. By contrast, the Apache Software Foundation has been around for 20 years and the Apache Way - the framework of values and governance for Apache Software Foundation projects - has been the guiding force for dozens of highly successful software projects that are used in countless environments everywhere, run much of the Internet, and are probably used by every technical person in one way or another every day.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The ASF and OFBiz - How Community Makes It All Possible</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1065.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1065.html</guid>
      <description>Going back well before the ASF was formed, community has played a vital role in the development of open source software. With the formation of the ASF, we see a great example of open source community being formalized and actively facilitated. Although it can seem counterintuitive, especially to the uninitiated, placing &amp;lsquo;Community over code&amp;rsquo; helps ensure the ongoing relevance of open source as a movement, inviting individuals and organizations alike to invest in &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; software.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Apache MXNet to Train and Deploy your Deep Learning model</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1094.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1094.html</guid>
      <description>AI is evolving rapidly, and much of the recent advancement is driven by Deep Learning, a machine learning technique inspired by the inner-working of the human brain. In this session, we will discuss what deep learning is, and the new capabilities it enables. We will dive into a few computer vision and natural language models that are demonstrating super-human performance, and to integrate these models into your existing Java system leveraging Apache MXNet - an open source deep learning framework – and it&amp;rsquo;s Java API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Kafka vs. Integration Middleware (MQ, ETL, ESB) - Friends, Enemies or Frenemies?</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1124.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1124.html</guid>
      <description>MQ, ETL and ESB middleware are often used as integration backbone between legacy applications, modern microservices and cloud services. This introduces several challenges and complexities like point-to-point integration or non-scalable architectures. This session discusses how to build a completely event-driven streaming platform leveraging Apache Kafka’s open source messaging, integration and streaming components to leverage distributed processing, fault-tolerance, rolling upgrades and the ability to reprocess events. nLearn the differences between an event-driven streaming platform leveraging Apache Kafka and middleware like MQ, ETL and ESBs – including best practices and anti-patterns, but also how these concepts and tools complement each other in an enterprise architecture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache NetBeans clever APIs for cross platform development</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1106.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1106.html</guid>
      <description>Hybrid applications can be a great solution for cross platform development, but JavaScript is not everyones cup of coffee. With a small set of clever APIs and SPIs, NetBeans has created a lean cross platform framework, that allows you to code in Java, and run the application on any mobile or desktop platform, as hybrid, or fully native application. In this sessions I&amp;rsquo;d like to unveil this hidden gem (improperly named &amp;lsquo;HTML/Java&amp;rsquo;), show some real life applications and discuss how this improves client side software development dramatically.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Toree: A Jupyter Kernel for Scala / Apache Spark</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1089.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1089.html</guid>
      <description>Many data scientists are already making heavy usage of the Jupyter ecosystem for analyzing data using interactive notebooks. Apache Toree (incubating) is a Jupyter kernel designed that enables data scientists and data engineers to easily connect and leverage Apache Spark and its powerful APIs from a standard Jupyter notebook to execute their analytics workloads. In this talk, we will go over what&amp;rsquo;s new with the most recent Apache Toree release. We will cover available magics and visualizations extensions that can be integrated with Toree to enable better data exploration and data visualizations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Driving dynamic Beam pipelines</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1317.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1317.html</guid>
      <description>Using Apache Beam to get data in your data lake? In a agile company you don’t want to re-compile your ingestion pipeline every time a sprint finished. In this talk we go over all mechanisms and building blocks you need to make dynamic pipelines really work. We’ll see why schemas are so important. How do we get these schemas in our pipelines and discuss methods to protect ourselves from data corruption and incompatible schema evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enterprise Hybrid Mobile App Development</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1202.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1202.html</guid>
      <description>This session shows how to develop and run native mobile apps without needing to know much about the native platforms, such as Android and iOS, by leveraging a hybrid development framework such as Apache Cordova, which is capable of transforming an ordinary web app into a mobile app. The presentation discusses a real-life enterprise-level Android and iOS mobile app developed under pressure for a wireless service provider. It covers some of the technical details of the app as well as how to perform device-level debugging of the Android app, using adb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How China Search Giant Baidu adopt apache way inside its company</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1092.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1092.html</guid>
      <description>Baidu is one of the biggest Internet company, it was founded 20 years ago with 10,000 more engineers now.nit began to embraces open source recently years, including adopting InnerSource and contributing to open source community. InnerSource is the use of apache ways inside the company. n As the leader of this program, I will talk about how this happened, and what&#39;s the challenges we faced and overcome. we need to set policies, define processes and enable tools , but the most important part is to cultivate open source culture, educate engineers what is apache way and how to cooperate inside company just like in open source community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Raise an Erudite Chatbot</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1014.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1014.html</guid>
      <description>Availability of content and training sets is a major bottleneck for a chatbot development today. Relying on Apache OpenNLP and its sub-project OpenNLP.chatbot, we introduce a number of tools and components to design a chatbot and its training set to be knowledgeable and intelligent. n In this talk we will analyze the reasons it is so hard to find a chatbot demo today for a nontrivial task or to observe an intelligent behavior of a chatbot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>OFBiz in the fashion Industry, an omnichannel approach</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1186.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1186.html</guid>
      <description>The fashion industry works to meet the demand for apparel and dictates thentrends for what should be worn.nThis presentation will describe why Apache OFBiz is a great platform fornbuilding an ERP for the fashion industry and how it can be enhanced tonsupport its specific requirements. The various implementation steps of anconcrete project will be reviewed:n- Development of a custom eCommerce/B2B Responsive and Seo compliantnapplication using the Color-Size matrix feature.n- Integration of third-party applications such as retail, legacy Erp,nsocial network, WMS, Business Intelligence, mailing system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running C* on Kubernetes with CassKop, the C* operator for K8S developed by Orange</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1101.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1101.html</guid>
      <description>This presentation will describe the initial experience building and using CassKop, an operator developed for running Cassandra on top of Kubernetes. CassKop works as a usual K8S controller (reconcile the real state with a desired state) and automates the Cassandra operations through JMX. All the operations are launched by calling standard K8S APIs (kubectl apply …) or by using a K8S plugin (kubectl casskop …). CassKop is developed in GO, based on CoreOS operator-sdk framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stream processing for the masses with Beam, Python and Flink</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1324.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1324.html</guid>
      <description>Python is a widely used programming language that is characterized by a low barrier to entry. As many other companies in the industry, Yelp has used Python as the main programming language to implement back-end services. Unfortunately, when it comes to stream processing Python presents several challenges, including performance limitations, lack of proper multi-threading support and limited framework options.
When the use cases for more advanced stream processing started to arise, at Yelp we decided to leverage Flink and introduce a Scala/Java stack for our Data Pipeline.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Streamlining Streaming System Management with Apache Heron</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1190.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1190.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Heron (Incubating) is a real-time, distributed, fault-tolerant stream processing engine. In 2018 it was donated to the Apache Foundation and is used for processing data sets in a way that allows systems to react to data as it is created. The big data era is here and it has become more critical than ever that organizations are able to make decisions based on the data they own in an efficient and accurate way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Arrow &#43; Apache Beam: A vision for cross-language, columnar data pipelines</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1323.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1323.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Arrow and Apache Beam deserve to be together. It is a stated goal of both projects to provide mechanisms for performing data processing tasks across many languages. To accomplish this, both projects define a common binary “model” and provide multiple language implementations of that model.
However, they are approaching the overarching problem of cross-language data processing from two very different angles: Arrow is primarily concerned with moving columnar data across language boundaries with minimal overhead and providing optimized computation primitives to operate on that data, while Beam seeks to enable users to write scalable data pipelines in their language of choice and execute them on any distributed data-processing system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Camel K: connect your Knative serverless applications with everything else</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1059.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1059.html</guid>
      <description>When you start developing serverless applications in the real world, sooner rather than later you will need to talk to external (legacy) systems. In this talk you will discover how to leverage Apache Camel K to connect your Knative serverless applications with everything Camel can connect.nApache Camel K allows running Camel routes as serverless applications directly on top of any Kubernetes cluster, leveraging Knative serverless capabilities such as auto-scaling, scaling to zero, event-based communication in order to connect serverless functions and microservice with external systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Cordova In Action</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1044.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1044.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Cordova is a platform for building Hybrid mobile apps using common Web technologies (HTML, CSS and JavaScript). Apache Cordova offers a set of APIs that allow the mobile app developers to utilize mobile native functions such as (Audio, Camera, Contacts …etc) using JavaScript. Ionic is one of the best mobile web application frameworks, which allows the web developers to develop neat mobile web applications. This session discusses why there is a need for Hybrid mobile development, the current challenges of mobile development, and how using Apache Cordova can help in overcoming many of these technical challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache NetBeans - Shameless Marketing Tool</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1123.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1123.html</guid>
      <description>NetBeans has completed its transition to Apache and is now a top level Apache project with a strong and dedicated community and millions of users worldwide. NetBeans always had great support for Apache Maven &amp;amp; having an IDE of our own is a great chance to further promote Apache projects to a large audience. In this session I&amp;rsquo;ll show you how to plugin your own language, tool, library, server, database or framework and make it easy for developers to get started with them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache OFBiz in the Cloud(s)</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1140.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1140.html</guid>
      <description>Cloud computing greatly simplifies provisioning, scaling, reliability and maintenance: these aspects are particularly important for Enterprise applications like Apache OFBiz. This talk will provide effective tips, based on experience and lessons learned in the field, to enable OFBiz for the cloud. Topics covered include OFBiz specific solutions for:n- deployments in AWSn- images - AMI, Dockern- continuous deploymentsn- configurations for load balancersn- session management - sticky sessions, distributed sessions (with Redis)n- database options for the cloud - RDS (AWS), Google Cloud Spanner</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Machine and Deep Learning at Scale with Apache Ignite</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1125.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1125.html</guid>
      <description>With most machine learning (ML) and deep learning (DL) frameworks, it can take hours to move data, and hours to train models. It&amp;rsquo;s also hard to scale, with data sets increasingly being larger than the capacity of any single server. The size of the data also makes it hard to incrementally test and retrain models in near real-time to improve results. Learn how Apache Ignite and GridGain help to address these limitations with model training and execution, and help achieve near-real-time, continuous learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Netflix debugs and fixes Apache Cassandra when it breaks</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1006.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1006.html</guid>
      <description>Netflix relies on Apache Cassandra as a critical source of truth database, and while Cassandra is a remarkably resilient database, it does, ever so occasionally, break. This talk explores how complex Cassandra deployments fail in production, but more importantly, the techniques, tools, and approaches our distributed systems engineers use to debug and mitigate these failures. We will first cover software-based failure modes that come either from our software or the software that Cassandra builds upon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Slide Your Release Pass the Incubator</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1096.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1096.html</guid>
      <description>All podling releases need to be voted on by the incubator PMC before being released to the world. I&amp;rsquo;ll go through what the incubator PMC looks for in every release and what you can do to make it pass that IPMC vote and get your project one step closer to graduation. More importantly I&amp;rsquo;ll cover where you can get help if you need it. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll describe current incubator and ASF policy, recent changes that you may not be aware of, and go into detail the legal requirements of common open source licenses and the best way to assemble your NOTICE and LICENSE files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Apache Flink and Apache Beam on Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1316.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1316.html</guid>
      <description>Access to real-time data is increasingly important for many organizations. At Lyft, we process millions of events per second in real-time to compute prices, balance marketplace dynamics, detect fraud, among many other use cases. To do so, we run dozens of Apache Flink and Apache Beam pipelines. Flink provides a powerful framework that makes it easy for non-experts to write correct, high-scale streaming jobs, while Beam extends that power to our large base of Python programmers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spoilt for Choice – Kafka Streams vs. KSQL for Stream Processing on top of Apache Kafka</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1195.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1195.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Kafka is a de facto standard streaming data processing platform. It is widely deployed as event streaming platform. Part of Kafka is its stream processing API “Kafka Streams”. In addition, the Kafka ecosystem now offers KSQL, a declarative, SQL-like stream processing language that lets you define powerful stream-processing applications easily. What once took some moderately sophisticated Java code can now be done at the command line with a familiar and eminently approachable syntax.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TVM: An Automated End-to-End Optimizing Compiler for Deep Learning</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1121.html</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1121.html</guid>
      <description>There is an increasing need to bring machine learning to a wide diversity of hardware devices from the datacenter to the edge. Current frameworks rely on vendor-specific operator libraries and optimize for a narrow range of server-class GPUs. Deploying workloads to new platforms such as mobile phones, embedded devices, and accelerators (e.g., FPGAs, ASICs) requires significant manual effort. In this talk, we will talk about Apache TVM &amp;ndash; an end to end optimizing deep compiler stack that brings deep learning models on diverse hardware back-ends that are competitive with state-of-the-art hand-tuned libraries for low-power CPU, mobile GPU, and server-class GPUs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Camel K: a cloud-native integration platform</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1142.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1142.html</guid>
      <description>In this session we are going to introduce the latest innovation from the Apache Camel community: Camel K, a lightweight integration platform, born on Kubernetes, with serverless superpowers.nCamel K enables developers that want to integrate systems to directly write Camel DSL code in the cloud, with a great developer experience and really fast turnaround times.nYou’ll see Camel K in action with a live coding demo that will explore the main features that it provides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache httpd reverse proxy and Tomcat:</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1156.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1156.html</guid>
      <description>Although mostly known as a fast and reliable web server, Apache httpd also excels as a reverse proxy.nIn this session find out how to setup httpd as a reverse proxy, how to connect to Tomcat using HTTP and AJP.nWe will also look to the full feature list of Apache httpd proxying capability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building Data Platform for your Next Meetup Event with Apache Foundation on Cloud</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1138.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1138.html</guid>
      <description>One of the challenges at Meetup is how to build a scalable, reliable and efficient data platform to help our ML team builds models that recommend events fit your interests. With emerging sophisticated batch and streaming frameworks and cloud solutions, our data platform went through massive changes in the past two years. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll discuss the evolution of how Meetup data platform utilizes Apache-based data systems, including Sqoop, Hive, Flume, Spark, Flink, Beam, Airflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consistent Cassandra schema changes in Elassandra</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1070.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1070.html</guid>
      <description>As described in CASSANDRA-10699 (Make schema alterations strongly consistent), concurrent schema changes can still lead to schema disagreement in Cassandra 3.0. In order to properly support Elasticsearch dynamic mapping in Elassandra, we will see how multiple schema changes are validated on a working copy of the Cassandra schema, and applied in an atomic update to all nodes if a light weight transaction succeed, thus avoiding concurrent schema changes issue. I will also explain how we have taken advantage of Cassandra table extensions to store the Elasticsearch mapping directly into the CQL schema with several benefits.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Exploring github data using Apache Drill running on ARM64</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1155.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1155.html</guid>
      <description>Inspired by Google&amp;rsquo;s Felipe Hoffa&amp;rsquo;s effort/talk, this attempt is to replicate an usecase of exploring github data using Apache Drill and lessons learnt. Apache Drill is a distributed MPP query layer that supports SQL and alternative query languages against NoSQL and Hadoop data storage systems. The talk will highlight steps to build Apache Drill from source code, and showcase a demo analyzing terabytes of github data (issues and comments), running on a cluster of 3 node ARM64 servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Happiness is a hybrid cloud with Apache Cassandra™</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1028.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1028.html</guid>
      <description>The world&amp;rsquo;s data and the speed with which we expect to access it continues to grow rapidly. Apache Cassandra was built for hybrid cloud implementations and that makes it easy for companies to fully exploit their cloud strategies without having to re-architect their applications or change their systems for data management. Sounds too good to be true? A lot of big companies have been doing it for years and you can too!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Podling&#39;s Shark Tank</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1038.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1038.html</guid>
      <description>Is it a panel? Is it a talk? It is a Podling&amp;rsquo;s Shark Tank! Back by popular demand with even sharkier judges! What is it, you ask? Well, this is just like Shark Tank TV show (think speed dating between entrepreneurs and investors) but instead of “Squirrel Boss” and “Man Candle” you&amp;rsquo;ll be hearing pitches for Apache Incubator projects. Also instead of Mark Cuban and Kevin O&amp;rsquo;Leary you&amp;rsquo;ll be pitching to the panel of ASF old timers (trying to convince them that your project is worthy of their esteemed attention and endorsement).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple, Portable data pipelines with Apache Beam SQL</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1309.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1309.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Beam is a unified data processing framework, allowing you to write batch and streaming pipelines that run anywhere, including Apache Flink, Apache Spark, and Google Cloud Dataflow. With the SQL extension you can now write a pipeline in pure SQL. If you need more, you can write user defined functions in Java or even embed SQL into your existing Java pipeline. This talk will start with a demo pipeline written in pure SQL.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Web-based Interactive Big Data Visualization</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1183.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 17:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1183.html</guid>
      <description>Data visualization is a challenging job to do in the Web-based environment due to the limited rendering efficiency of Web browsers. Rendering big data and providing user interaction in real time is even more challenging. nIn this speech, we are going to introduce how we made this possible with ECharts, a popular Web-based data visualization tool. Generally speaking, the solution lies in the following four aspects:n1. Simplifying shapes and rendering faster but with a similar result.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Kibble Crash Course</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1099.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1099.html</guid>
      <description>This presentation aims at showcasing the Apache Kibble project, getting new users set up with their own Kibble instance and getting started with project and community metrics. During this talk, the audience will learn what Apache Kibble is, what it does, HOW it does it, and how you can easily get set up in a few minutes and start reviewing metrics from your own project. We will also show a demo instance with a select handful of Apache projects, and dive into both single community metrics as well as comparative measuring across foundations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Combining schema-on-read and schema-provisioning in Apache Drill</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1185.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1185.html</guid>
      <description>The data generated from IoT devices, machine logs and similar sources is often semi-structured or unstructured. This poses a challenge for traditional schema-on-write systems that require a fixed schema up-front for querying. Modern analytic applications often have ad hoc usage patterns and require tremendous flexibility over how this data can be consumed. Further, they demand that the data be made available for querying soon after it has landed in their data platform – which may be a distributed file system or NoSQL database or something similar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing new IO connectors in Apache Beam</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1308.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1308.html</guid>
      <description>One of the key components in any data processing system is IO connectors. These fundamental blocks allow to read and write data, which is stored in different type of sources, in a unified and distributed way. In this sense, Apache Beam is not an exception - it provides a rich API to develop a new connector with your favorite SDK and easily integrate it with Beam runners. In this talk we are going to show you how to write your own IO connector (in Java).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Efficient data integrations with the Medley platform</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1034.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1034.html</guid>
      <description>In this talk, we will introduce the Medley data integration platform used at Uber. Medley is based on the Apache Camel framework, and centered around integrating internal systems efficiently and with great precision on multiple network environments. We will focus on the concept of reusability of integrations, where integrations can be securely shared by implementing integrations as web services. Also, implementing business entity change detection with publish/subscribe to changes to allow event based integrations based on data state changes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From Postgres to an In-Memory Grid with Apache Ignite</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1147.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1147.html</guid>
      <description>This talk describes how a food tech company with 50k merchants was at a critical situation by delivering events to devices by using events polling on a Postgres database, and how it could solve this problem by moving the events repository to Apache Ignite using distributed, in-memory SQL. The change also allowed the company to be on the right track to support more than 500k simultaneous merchants.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Love Lucee</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1148.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1148.html</guid>
      <description>Lucee is a free and open source application server that implements the CFML language, which was popularized by the commercial product ColdFusion. It allows for rapid application development, and is implemented as a JSP Servlet so it is deployed inside a Servlet Container like Apache Tomcat. The Lucee website: https://lucee.org/ GitHub Repo:nhttps://github.com/lucee/Lucee Support Forum: https://dev.lucee.org/</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instaclustr&#39;s Open Source Tools For Cassandra - LDAP/Kerberos, Prometheus Exporter, Debug Tooling and K8s Operator</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1026.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1026.html</guid>
      <description>This session walks devs through Instaclustr&amp;rsquo;s Cassandra tools and how they add key functionality and ease-of-use to their deployments.n- An LDAP authenticator plug-in for CassandranThe open source LDAP authenticator plug-in works closely with the existing CassandraAuthorizer implementation. The plug-in enables developers to quickly reap the benefits of secure LDAP authentication without the need to write their own solutions, and to transition to using the authenticator with zero downtime. - A Kerberos authenticator plug-in for CassandranThe open source Kerberos authenticator plug-in enables Cassandra users to leverage Kerberos’ industry-leading secure authentication and true single sign-on capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mission Critical Cassandra in Financial Services, The When/What/How Experiences for ALL!</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1110.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1110.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Cassandra is a database product that is most notably known for being highly scalable and fault tolerant. Since these characteristics are something that is desirable in almost every use case, it attracts attention from developers up through executives when faced with decisions on how to architect mission critical systems. If these traits are so desirable, and Apache Cassandra makes these capabilities available to end users, then shouldn’t we use Cassandra for all our data storage needs?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Samza 1.0: How we scaled stream processing at LinkedIn</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1182.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 16:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1182.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;At LinkedIn, we generate a staggering 2 trillion events to Kafka each day. nThe ingested events are processed by our streaming platform powered by Apache Samza. nWe currently have over 3000 applications in production that leverage Samza at LinkedIn. nThe use-cases include the LinkedIn feed, anomaly detection, combating fraud, profile notifications, realtime analytics and many more. In this talk, we will describe our journey in building and scaling a distributed stream nprocessing system over these years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>(Apache) Drill-ing into Collections of HDF5 Files</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1069.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1069.html</guid>
      <description>This talk is about building bridges between two ecosystems, Apache and HDF5.nHDF5 is a widely used storage container for complex data from embedded devicesnto supercomputers, and is developed and maintained as FOSS by The HDF Group.nWhile it is easy to imagine the potential benefits of making HDF5 containersnaccessible from the various Apache frameworks, there are several technicalnchallenges to overcome, and what makes a &amp;lsquo;good&amp;rsquo; integration is by no meansnobvious. It requires the input and collaboration of experts from both sides.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Tomcat / HTTPD Configuration Management</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1122.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1122.html</guid>
      <description>Does your organization have tons of applications and containers? Has this fleet grown to be completely unmanageable? Do undocumented changes cause downtime and pain for your operations? Using modern configuration management tools and practices (Chef and CI/CD), Mastercard created a set of cookbooks that builds, deploys and manages model driven middleware infrastructure. Join us for a talk where we will discuss what is and why you should do configuration management, how we chose to model the middleware configurations, examples of how to test the heck out of the whole assembly and how this methodology brings everything a step closer to “gitops”.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building S3 over Ozone : Making a Cloud Native File System</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1104.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1104.html</guid>
      <description>The AWS S3 protocol is the defacto interface for modern object stores. Ozone supports S3 protocol as the first-class notion in Ozone. For all practical purposes, a user of S3 can start using Ozone without any change to code or tools. S3 protocol support offered by Ozone is strongly consistent, so users don’t need to run sidekick tools like S3Guard when running big data applications like Apache Spark, Apache YARN or Apache Hive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DataSketches - The Required Toolkit for the Analysis of Big Data</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1181.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1181.html</guid>
      <description>In​ the analysis of b​ig data there are often problem queries that don’t scale because they require huge compute resources to generate exact results, or don’t parallelize well. Examples include c​ount-distinct, ​quantiles, most frequent items, joins, matrix computations, and graph analysis. Algorithms that can produce accuracy guaranteed approximate answers for these problem queries are a required toolkit for modern analysis systems that need to process massive amounts of data​ quickly. For interactive queries there may not be other viable alternatives, and in the case of real­-time streams, these specialized algorithms, called stochastic, s​treaming, sublinear algorithms,​ or &amp;lsquo;s​ketches&amp;rsquo;,​ are the only known solution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Day to day with Cassandra: The weirdest and complex situations we found!</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1126.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1126.html</guid>
      <description>Every Cassandra operator has been hit with a couple of weird/complex cases that don&amp;rsquo;t fit the normal expected failure situation. It can be a problem in hardware, software, networking, operator mistake, or a mix of it all. In this talk we will go through a compilation of such cases that we faced. How do they appear, how did we debug them and how did we fix them. We expect this to be a walk through weird, fun cases and sharing knowledge on the situations and on the fixing of such problems</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons from the Apache Beam Journey</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1024.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1024.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Beam is a big data processing framework that can run on multiple big data engines, including Apache Spark, Apache Flink, Apache Samza, Apache Apex, and a number of non-Apache OSS engines and proprietary engines. After situating Beam in the OSS ecosystem, I will share lessons from Apache Beam&amp;rsquo;s journey, including topics such as: - how do you onboard newcomers to the Apache Way?n - how is open source different / the same as internal corporate work?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mythbusting with Apache Cassandra</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1302.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1302.html</guid>
      <description>As a mature operational database with a 10+ year history as an Apache project, Cassandra has a long history with many twists and turns. In this talk, we’ll look at common misgivings and misunderstandings that we encounter in conversations with developers and get to the bottom of the story:
 Cassandra is a “columnar” (or “column-oriented”) database. Porting my relational data model to Cassandra will work well. Cassandra is a niche database that is only good for narrow set of use cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of integration with Apache Camel</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1141.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1141.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Camel is the leading open source integration framework, which has been around for over a decade. In this talk we will look back in history, to understand how the integration landscape has evolved from EAI, SOA, and ESB architectures up to microservices, and now with modern serverless and cloud native platforms. Apache Camel has been along for the ride. And we will look to the future and see how the latest release v3 of Apache Camel, is aimed for running modern cloud native workloads with Camel K.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The journey of building a Beam runner based on Spark structured streaming framework</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1307.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 15:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1307.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Beam provides a unified programming model to execute batch and streaming pipelines on all the popular big data engines. The translation layer from Beam to the chosen big data engine is called a runner. The current runner for Apache Spark is based on the RDD/DStream framework. However, there is an ongoing work to move it to Spark next generation framework a.k.a structured streaming. This talk will present why structured streaming is a good fit for Apache Beam, why it is worth the effort, and will give some feedback on how Apache Beam has solved the challenge, what the tough points and the sweet points were.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra at Instagram 2019</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1074.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1074.html</guid>
      <description>At Instagram, our mission is to capture and share the world&amp;rsquo;s moments. Our app is used by over 1 billion people monthly; this creates a lot of challenging data needs. We use Cassandra behind a lot of different product features. In this presentation, I will talk about how we use Cassandra to serve our critical use cases; the improvements we made in last several years to make sure Cassandra can meet our low latency, high scalability requirements; and future plans.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Declarative Benchmarking of Cassandra and Its Data Models</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1025.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1025.html</guid>
      <description>You have made changes to Cassandra code base. How do you benchmark these changes for scalability and correctness, including different data models (schema), easily? You have created a Cassandra schema for your service. How do you ensure this is scalable? How can you emulate application specific CQL queries, with specified distribution, to validate scale of your schema and associated data scalability without having to code your whole application? I am the author of the NDBench CQL Plugin tool, which was built at Netflix to address these needs and more, Declaratively.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Drilling Security Data</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1050.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1050.html</guid>
      <description>Security data is often challenging to analyze because it comes in a variety of formats that are difficult and time consuming to parse, requiring a myriad of various tools to analyze this data. Additionally, bringing this data together to correlate multiple data sets can be difficult and extremely time consuming. But what if all your data could be queried with single tool, using a common language? This talk will demonstrate how to use Apache Drill&amp;rsquo;s enormous analytic power on security data sets and visualize this data using Apache Superset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HTTP/2, HTTP/3 and SSL/TLS State of Art in Our Servers</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1135.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1135.html</guid>
      <description>A new protocol is getting ready HTTP/3 we will look to where we are with it in our serves.nThe &amp;lsquo;old&amp;rsquo; HTTP/2 protocol and the corresponding TLS/SSL are common to Traffic Server, HTTP Server and Tomcat.nThe presentation will shortly explain the new protocol and the ALPN extensions and look to the state of the those in our 3 servers and show the common parts and the specifics of each servers.nA demo configuration of each server will be run.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Protect your Private Data in your Hadoop Clusters with ORC Column Encryption</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1066.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1066.html</guid>
      <description>Fine-grained data protection at a column level in data lake environments has become a mandatory requirement to demonstrate compliance with multiple local and international regulations across many industries today. ORC is a self-describing type-aware columnar file format designed for Hadoop workloads that provides optimized streaming reads, but with integrated support for finding required rows quickly. In this talk, we will outline the progress made in Apache community for adding fine-grained column level encryption natively into ORC format that will also provide capabilities to mask or redact data on write while protecting sensitive column metadata such as statistics to avoid information leakage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SPARQL at scale with Apache Rya</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1080.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1080.html</guid>
      <description>The Resource Description Framework (RDF) is a standard model for storing graph data. While the standard was initially created for storing meta-data about the World Wide Web, its flexible format made it a popular choice for storing many different types of information. With the explosive increase in the size of available data, scalable solutions are needed to efficiently store and query very large RDF graphs within big data architectures. Apache Rya (incubating) is a scalable database management system designed for storing and searching very large RDF data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Rise of Open Source Software (and Apache projects) in China</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1021.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1021.html</guid>
      <description>This talk will cover the evolution, the current status and the outlook of the China open source landscape and ecosystem. This talk will also share the summary and analysis of varies open source software survey reports for China, the largest software developers market in the world. The Apache Software Foundation&amp;rsquo;s projects and their communities play a critical role in leading and developing the OSS ecosystems in China where some leading IT enterprises and individuals, such as Huawei, Alibaba, Baidu, Tencent, Kyligence, SkyWalking, etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Relational Cache to Boost Apache Spark SQL</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1180.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1180.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Spark has become a popular engine for data analysis in industry, providing a handful SQL interface and processing data from various data sources. While many of our customers are using Apache Spark as an interactive query platform to meet their business requirement, one of the most common complaints we heard is that spark is not quite &amp;lsquo;interactive&amp;rsquo; while data goes big. In traditional database systems, we can utilize materialized views to accelerate query processing, through pre-computation and query plan rewriting.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the Timer and State API to solve times series use case in Apache Beam</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1306.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 14:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1306.html</guid>
      <description>Time series processing requires ordered processing of data points, often across windows boundaries. Tricky stuff for distributed processing systems, in this chat we look at how to solve for these problems using a combination of Global Windows, State and the Timer API&#39; with Apache Beam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache When You’re Not In Charge</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1151.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1151.html</guid>
      <description>Apache has a 20 year history of building resilient and sustainable communities of software developers through the Apache Way. While some companies are adopting Inner sourcing, other companies still have a taboo surrounding open source culture. Many of us work at these open source agnostic companies and don’t have manager in our title. Are those of us in those companies doomed to a life of Dilbert? You don’t have to be!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friendlier Communities Through Infrastructure: Apache Beam’s Journey</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1305.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1305.html</guid>
      <description>In this talk we will discuss the infrastructure Apache Beam has built to create a positive contributor experience. Over the last few years we have developed tooling, refactored code, instrumented Jenkins builds, collected metrics, created a metrics dashboard, and involved the community in order to ensure happy contributors. We will discuss the importance of engineering productivity and tooling in developing strong communities, where we have succeeded, and where we still have work to do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Game Changing Operational Visibility tools in Apache Cassandra 4.0</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1184.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1184.html</guid>
      <description>In this talk, we will review the new and upcomming tools for Apache Cassandra operations. This talk will go over some of the new and soon to be tools for operational visibility. Specific areas covered will include:n- Different operational tasks will be exposed with an HTTP interface with the sidecarn- Virtual tables provides visibility to the state of a node with cqlshn- New commands added to nodetool and JMX See how these improvements and additions will give operation teams faster diagnostics to assist in discovering problematic clients and data models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons Learned from Leveraging Real-Time Power Consumption Data with Apache Kudu</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1179.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1179.html</guid>
      <description>IoT is widely spreading in various industries, and various sensor devices generate large amounts of data in real-time. Such big data is used for visualization, machine learning, and other data analysis. Kudu is one of the data stores for such use cases which require fast inserts and efficient scans. Apache HBase is also often used to handle time series data such as sensor data. We also evaluated HBase for smart meter data a few years ago.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modernizing the Nordstrom Supply Chain: Efficient Order Fulfillment using JanusGraph, Cassandra and Spark</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1102.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1102.html</guid>
      <description>DESCRIPTION: Today&amp;rsquo;s Nordstrom customers expect order fulfillment options shipping to the most convenient locations in the timeframes that best fit their schedules. This session offers an inside look at how Nordstrom&amp;rsquo;s Supply Chain Technology team combined an extensive network of brick and mortar facilities with a custom software stack built atop JanusGraph to present fulfillment options tailored to each individual order. ABSTRACT: Over the last decade, the volume of online retail sales as a proportion of overall retail sales has nearly tripled, and there are no signs of this trend slowing down.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Packaging Tomcat for Linux Distributions</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1004.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1004.html</guid>
      <description>What is the difference between the ASF Tomcat distribution and the various flavors of tomcat packages on Linux? Most users don’t know! In this discussion Coty will explain how the tomcat packages distributed by a couple flavors of Linux (Red Hat and Debian/Ubuntu) are structured and why the container is provided that way. Coty also hopes to get feedback from the audience and to discuss how these Linux distributions can better provide tomcat to users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schema-Controlled HDFS Column Encryption and Use Cases</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1132.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1132.html</guid>
      <description>Motivation: Access control via encryption improves security coverage compared with traditional enforcement in the access path because encryption can prevent invalid accesses from any angle. Finer-grained access control at the column-level is needed because in a typical big dataset, only a few columns are sensitive and need to be protected, and different columns could have different sensitivities and a different set of eligible readers. Design: With encryption features in columnar file format like Apache Parquet, column access control via encryption becomes possible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Supporting Cassandra In-House – Our Story !!</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1008.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1008.html</guid>
      <description>In this presentation, senior Cassandra Architects at Ericsson will share their vast experience in supporting around 100 Cassandra deployments in production. They will share the key challenges and best practices with respect to Cassandra operations, maintenance and support. There is plenty to learn when the team talks about many problems which they faced in production and how they fixed each one of them successfully by providing interesting solutions. Audience: All Cassandra users especially Cassandra operators and administrators.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What’s Surprising about Apache Drill and Why That’s a Challenge</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1052.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1052.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Apache Drill has some very surprising characteristics and, more importantly, it enables Drill users to do some surprising things. It’s no longer surprising to be able to do standard SQL in a highly distributed and large scale system - there is an entire class of modern tools that do this including Apache Hive, Presto or Spark SQL. But Drill has other capabilities that are surprising and make it stand apart from its class.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hadoop 3.x State of The Union and Upgrade Guidance</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1049.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1049.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Apache Hadoop YARN is the modern Distributed Operating System for big data applications. It morphed the Hadoop compute layer to be a common resource-management platform that can host a wide variety of applications. Many organizations leverage YARN in building their applications on top of Hadoop without themselves repeatedly worrying about resource management, isolation, multi-tenancy issues etc. The Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS) is the primary data storage system used by Hadoop applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Tomcat, your webapp, and the Graal</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1048.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1048.html</guid>
      <description>Graal&amp;rsquo;s native image generation has been the focus of a lot of attention recently, despite being in the very early stages. This session will look at the Tomcat embedded packaging, how to handle your webapp, and will demo use of Graal and Tomcat in a container environment. The session will mostly be tutorial/demo oriented, after a brief overview of the concept and tools used.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building BigData Query Optimization with Apache Calcite – Best Practices from Alibaba MaxCompute</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1178.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1178.html</guid>
      <description>MaxCompute is a large scale, distributed big data platform of Alibaba, which provides Exabyte storage capacity and massive computing power through tens of thousands of commodity machines. The system supports SQL-like declarative language for advanced query and analysis on web-scale data set. Millions of jobs with hundreds of petabytes of data are processed every day, powering mission critical business within Alibaba, including e-Commerce, mobile payment, logistics, etc. Query optimizer plays a key part in determining the optimal execution plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Trillions of Rows with Aplomb (well, actually with Drill)</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1022.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1022.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Ingesting lots of data isn’t very hard any more. Ingesting it on a critical schedule, within strict time bounds while minimizing the risk of bogus data showing up is much harder. In practice, grownup data ingestion and access requires the following capabilities * Incoming data can be fully ingested into our working dataset but hidden from users until all quality checks are completedn * Individual batches of data can be released atomicallyn * Any indexing updates should also appear appear atomicallyn * Expiring data should disappear atomically either according to ingest batch or precise time bounds Apache Drill provides several capabilities that make it much easier to meet these goals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Portable Spark Runner: Running Beam Pipelines Written in Python and Go with Spark</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1304.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1304.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Spark is the most popular open source analytics engine for large-scale data processing. Spark is not only a mature system, but thanks to its support of multiple resource managers like Hadoop, Mesos, and Kubernetes it has become a popular choice for both batch and streaming workloads in the industry. Apache Beam has included a Spark runner since its inception to allow users to execute Beam pipelines on Spark, but until recently the Spark runner could only execute pipelines written in Java.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Apache TinkerPop4 Virtual Machine</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1060.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1060.html</guid>
      <description>The Apache TinkerPop team is working on the next major version of the project &amp;ndash; TinkerPop4. TinkerPop4 advances the technology developed in TinkerPop3 with a new virtual machine architecture that enables any query language to control any processing engine manipulating any data structure. A query language can support a compiler to TinkerPop4&amp;rsquo;s Turing Complete bytecode specification. Compiled bytecode is then translated into an intermediate functional representation that an integrated processing engine will ultimately transform into a processor-specific execution plan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The State of Diversity in Open Source &amp; the ASF</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1023.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1023.html</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;d like to cover the landscape of D&amp;amp;I in tech, then in open source, and then in the ASF. I&amp;rsquo;d like to discuss the dimensions used to evaluate our current status and I&amp;rsquo;d like to discuss the efforts we&amp;rsquo;re working on to changer things. I will like to give this talk in the general track to a) celebrate the 20th Anniversary by reflecting back in our wins on diversity and inclusion and b) make it part of the foundation&amp;rsquo;s big picture</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Two years in the making: What’s new with Apache Cassandra 4.0?</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1027.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1027.html</guid>
      <description>At almost two years in the making Apache Cassandra 4.0 is almost here. With a focus on performance and stability, it is full of interesting features. This talk takes you through a tour of the new features and performance improvements. From Zero Copy Faster Streaming support to Virtual Tables and Audit Logging, learn how Apache Cassandra 4.0 has departed from previous major releases to be focused on the features required by the most demanding users.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using the TLP toolchain as a crystal ball for your cluster</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1068.html</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2019 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1068.html</guid>
      <description>Cassandra cluster management is hard. Understanding how your Cassandra data model will hold up in production over a period of time can be tricky. If that is not tough enough, understanding how a change to a Cassandra setting will affect your cluster can be be difficult. Knowing how your data model or setting change will perform under a production data load can prevent performance degradation or worse nodes going down. In the last year, The Last Pickle has invested the time to develop the tooling necessary to create test clusters in AWS, as well as a scalable stress tool which can run pre-configured workloads.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anomaly Prediction in Apache CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1017.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1017.html</guid>
      <description>There is a chance of system, storage and network failures in the CloudStack environment at any point of time, which is unknown to the end users and administrators. The administrators are highly depend on the alert and monitoring system to raise an alarm on failures, upon the action is being taken. This can down the operations and will impact the end user services. The prediction of such failures ahead in CloudStack environment would be required instead of depending on the monitoring systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache@Google, an account of the success of open source practices at Google Cloud</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1333.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1333.html</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ll share with the Apache Community the journey that Google Cloud has had since we donated the first project to the foundation. We&amp;rsquo;ll share our experiences from the commercial vendor point of view and also what we have learned while trying to embrace an &amp;ldquo;open source first&amp;rdquo; culture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building and running cloud-native Cassandra</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1075.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1075.html</guid>
      <description>This session will re-evaluate Cassandra’s relationship with runtime and build systems, pointing out ways that the existing systems fall down, and identifying avenues for improvement. Over the past few years, a number of platforms have emerged for running user code. Container runtimes like Docker, container orchestrators such as Kubernetes, and metrics collections agents like Prometheus and Spectator have all gained popularity and mind-share. Cassandra functionality such as metrics, bootstrapping, and monitoring integrates with the newer paradigms, but in an ad-hoc and improvised fashion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hadoop Storage in the Cloud Native Era</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1177.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1177.html</guid>
      <description>Hadoop was born much earlier than the Cloud Native era. But the question is still the same: what can it offer in the time of Kubernetes, containerization and hybrid clouds? Apache Hadoop Ozone is a new subproject of Hadoop. It is based a generic low-level binary layer, the Hadoop Distributed Data Storage (HDDS) and a S3 compatible Object Store implementation on top of it. The separation of the data storage layer has multiple benefits: it can help to solve the “small files problem” and increase the scalability of the Hadoop storage clusters but it also helps us to provide access to the same data via multiple interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Grow Communities, Not Just Code</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1084.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1084.html</guid>
      <description>Good code isn&amp;rsquo;t enough for a successful open source project. First of all, only you know how to use what you&amp;rsquo;ve made. Maybe it&amp;rsquo;s time for a little UI and UX help? At the very least some documentation! Next, how is anyone else going to find what you&amp;rsquo;ve created? And that&amp;rsquo;s only the beginning. Ruth Suehle, manager of Red Hat&amp;rsquo;s Open Source and Standards community leadership team, will take you through examples of the best and the worst, from projects large and small, to help you see what you need beyond your code to build a successful open source project and community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Inside Apache Druid: Built for High-Performance Real-Time Analytics</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1171.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1171.html</guid>
      <description>Interactive applications are replacing traditional reporting interfaces as the preferred means for organizations to derive value from their datasets. An interactive user experience requires latency on the order of milliseconds. Cluster computing frameworks such as Apache Hadoop or Apache Spark are tremendously beneficial in processing and deriving insights from data. However, high query latency makes these frameworks sub-optimal for interactive applications. Alternatively, the use of relational databases and key/value stores as dedicated query layers can reduce latency, but these approaches suffer many drawbacks for analytic use cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introducing Secure Boot in Apache CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1036.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1036.html</guid>
      <description>nExisting CloudStack supports legacy boot loader BIOS by default for Guest VM’s booting on Hypervisor(XEN, VMware, KVM etc). In Virtualization, hypervisor emulates the hardware for the Guest VM. BIOS {Basic Input-Output system} is a low-level software. The BIOS loads when a VM starts up, and the BIOS is responsible for waking up your VM’s hardware(emulated) components, ensures they are functioning properly, and then runs the boot loader that boots Windows or whatever other operating system have installed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Standardizing Industrial IoT with Apache PLC4X, Apache Daffodil, and DFDL</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1081.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1081.html</guid>
      <description>Industrial IoT is made up of many different programmable logic controllers (PLCs) that communicate with often incompatible and proprietary data formats. Apache PLC4X standardizes access to these PLCs by creating a set of libraries across a variety of languages to read and write PLC data with a unified API. Unfortunately, developing and maintaining support for these different data formats, especially across multiple languages, can be burdensome. In this talk we discuss how we can describe PLC data using the open standard Data Format Description Language (DFDL), how Apache Daffodil uses these descriptions to transform data to a standard and easily consumable representation, and an approach to extend PLC4X to use Daffodil and DFDL descriptions to reduce the effort needed to support a variety of PLCs and languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Testing Contributions at Scale</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1211.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1211.html</guid>
      <description>Time may be one of the most valuable resources in a project. Automating code reviews to allow for other tasks is a crucial goal for many communities. This talk will cover one way many Apache projects have significantly increased code quality and contribution feedback while simultaneously doing more with less.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tomcat from a cluster to a cloud.</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1083.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1083.html</guid>
      <description>Using Tomcat in a cluster and in a cloud. nWe start by looking how to configure tomcat to get a cluster andnthen explore the problems and solutions to have distributed applications running in a cloud. Most cloud providers now have a Kubernetes API.nWe will look to what we have to add to Tomcat to have a decent cloud supportnfor monitoring, tracing and operating on the cloud.nWe will show how to use all the pieces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Watching TV on the command line with Apache Traffic Control</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1005.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 18:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1005.html</guid>
      <description>Watch closely as a CDN built with the components of Apache Traffic Control comes alive in the delivery of fragmented ABR video. This session will walk through every step in a CDN transaction using command line tools that simulate what real-world clients do behind-the-scenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Doris (incubating) -- A simple and single tightly coupled olap system</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1170.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1170.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Doris (incubating) is an MPP-based interactive SQL data warehousing for reporting and analysis. It is open-sourced by Baidu. Doris mainly integrates the technology of Google Mesa and Apache Impala. Unlike other popular SQL-on-Hadoop systems, Doris is designed to be a simple and single tightly coupled system, not depending on other systems. Doris not only provides high concurrent low latency point query performance, but also provides high throughput queries of ad-hoc analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Training - Contributing more than just code</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1172.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1172.html</guid>
      <description>Does it seem strange to you that we collectively collaborate on code but training material is produced individually in private? Why would each company or person produce their own material when it can be sourced from a central location, under a business friendly license, and built on and modified? Or perhaps you just see better ways of producing content, then come along and listen to what the Apache Training project is doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CloudStack Monitoring - In-Depth Checks For Production Deployments</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/3002.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/3002.html</guid>
      <description>This talk is for CloudStack administrators who&amp;rsquo;re responsible for maintaining a robust and fault-free production deployment. It covers monitoring fine grained parameters of a CloudStack installation and how to measure and check not just discrete values but also routinely performed actions against their expected outcome. It also dwells upon how the same discrete values make a difference from an access perspective. Whether you want to auto-resolve common problems, provide an SLA or just keep a tab on your deployment, this talk will definitely provide some insights.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Does Open Source Participation Get Easier Over Time?</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1115.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1115.html</guid>
      <description>What’s it like to be a committed member of an active open source community? What are the awesome parts? What are the challenges? Is open source for you? In this talk, presenters with a wide range of experience at Apache will share their stories and advice on open source participation. From starting out to ongoing involvement, from participating in open source as part of your job, to finding time to participate outside of your job, from finding models and mentors in an online, asynchronous communication environment to being such a mentor, from the worst to the best moments and experiences in open source, join us to hear about more than 30 years of combined experience with Apache projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World! Introducing Apache IoTDB - a Database for the Internet of Things</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1078.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1078.html</guid>
      <description>Time series data management system is becoming increasingly important with the rise of the Internet of Things, especially in the industrial area. Apache IoTDB (incubating), one of the youngest projects in the Apache Incubator, is born for that!nApache IoTDB is an integrated data management engine designed for time series data, based on a file format which is able to store time series data very efficiently. It provides users specific services for data collection, storage and analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes on BareMetal with Apache CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1007.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1007.html</guid>
      <description>nCloudStack currently supports Kubernetes deployment using Hypervisors, which enables PaaS on top of IaaS. However, PaaS applications having data-heavy loads are the most likely to be negatively impacted, especially when the service is oversubscribed. This is where BareMetal cloud offers a significant advantage over Hypervisors, especially for latency-sensitive workloads. This talk and demo will provide turnkey solution for integrating Kubernetes on CloudStack using BareMetal servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Locking Down Apache Tomcat: Practical Security for Real-world Applications</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1003.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1003.html</guid>
      <description>Out of the box, Apache Tomcat is quite secure. Then you need to configure it to suit your environment, connect your data sources, and deploy your applications. Those processes can potentially reduce the security of the entire system. A thorough review of your host, network, application and configuration is necessary to identify those areas where your security needs improvement. We’ll discuss each of these areas in some detail and how some simple tweaks and tools can make you and your users safer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ozone: Evolving HDFS Scalability to new heights &amp; built-in GDPR Compliance</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1176.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1176.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Hadoop Ozone is a robust, distributed key-value object store for Hadoop with layered architecture and strong consistency. It separates the namespace management from block and node management layer, which allows users to independently scale on both axes. Ozone is interoperable with Hadoop ecosystem as it provides OzoneFS (Hadoop compatible file system API), data locality and plug-n-play deployment with HDFS as it can be installed in an existing Hadoop cluster and can share storage disks with HDFS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing CDN Logging Events at Scale</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1199.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1199.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Content Delivery Networks generate staggering amounts of event data at a rate that is exponentially increasing in line with the explosion of IP video. Managing this deluge with the usual suspects of Big Data platforms presents a formidable challenge, particularly in light of the often-competing goals of detailed troubleshooting investigation versus big picture analytics and machine learning. This presentation will explore capturing and processing events from the largest production deployment of Apache Traffic Server and Apache Traffic Control.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transaction Management on Cassandra</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1139.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1139.html</guid>
      <description>Scalar DB is an open source library released under Apache 2 which realizes ACID-compliant transactions on Cassandra, without requiring any modifications to Cassandra itself. It achieves strongly-consistent, linearly scalable, and highly available transactions. This talk will present the theory and practice behind Scalar DB, as well as providing some benchmark results and use cases.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unleashing Apache Kafka and TensorFlow in Hybrid Cloud Architectures</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1160.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1160.html</guid>
      <description>How can you leverage the flexibility and extreme scale in the public cloud combined with your Apache Kafka ecosystem to build scalable, mission-critical machine learning infrastructures, which span multiple public clouds or bridge your on-premise data centre to cloud? nThis talk will discuss and demo how you can leverage machine learning technologies such as TensorFlow with your Kafka deployments in public cloud to build a scalable, mission-critical machine learning infrastructure for data ingestion and processing, and model training, deployment and monitoring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Pinot (incubating): Building Realtime Analytics Applications at LinkedIn Scale</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1169.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1169.html</guid>
      <description>LinkedIn is the most advantageous social networking tool available to job seekers and business professionals today, with 610+ million members creating millions of posts, videos, and articles that generate tens of millions of shares, comments and likes per day. LinkedIn has leveraged this activity data to build rich interactive user-facing analytics applications like “Who Viewed My Profile”, Talent Insights, Ad Analytics and Publisher Analytics, among others. These applications are all powered by Pinot, as are internal dashboards, anomaly detection and root cause analysis platform like ThirdEye.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cassandra: Partition Management</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1093.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1093.html</guid>
      <description>(Cassandra NGCC) Apache Cassandra on-disk storage model is based on immutable SSTables that are, depending on the compaction strategy, optimized for some general use cases. The main issue with optimally reading on-disk data is that a single partition data most of the time needs to be fetched from multiple partitions. None of the existing compaction strategies are optimized to provide a single file read guarantees on cold data. Partition based compaction strategy addresses that issue with effectively compacting all data that belongs to a single partition into the same SSTable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CloudStack identity federation: An overview</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1144.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1144.html</guid>
      <description>Federated authentication in online services is increasingly being used, whether through public identity providers such as Facebook, Google and others, or in organizations&#39; private identity providers. Identity federation is a technology that has come to simplify the life of the user, but that does not always simplify the life of application developers and operators. The purpose of this talk is to share a bit the challenges, benefits and problems of using federated authentication with multiple identity providers in Apache Cloudstack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity, a beginners introduction</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1071.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1071.html</guid>
      <description>Diversity and inclusion are becoming hot topics within our open source communities and industry, but for those of us &amp;lsquo;playing life on easy&amp;rsquo;, the subject and impact can be harder to &amp;lsquo;get&amp;rsquo;. Like many people who used to play life on easy, I&amp;rsquo;ve had some blind spots around diversity and inclusion. I only discovered these through working on projects, communities and support at the ASF, and by moving to a new country!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving the Observability of Cassandra, Kafka and Kubernetes applications with Prometheus and OpenTracing</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1031.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1031.html</guid>
      <description>As distributed applications grow more complex, dynamic, and massively scalable, “observability” becomes more critical. Observability is the practice of using metrics, monitoring and distributed tracing to understand how a system works. In this presentation we’ll explore two complementary Open Source technologies: Prometheus for monitoring application metrics; and OpenTracing and Jaeger for distributed tracing. We’ll discover how they improve the observability of a massively scalable Anomaly Detection system - an application which is built around Apache Cassandra and Apache Kafka for the data layers, and dynamically deployed and scaled on Kubernetes, a container orchestration technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning applications for CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1108.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1108.html</guid>
      <description>While Machine learning and data mining has had profound impact on how we model applications and use data for better product consumption, there is scope for extending prediction algorithms to lower levels as well. Some useful applications of machine learning in ACS could be exploring better resource allocation that is aware of usage statistics, predicting faults, load balancing, etc. In this talk we will * take a broad overview of what Machine Learning/Data mining is and how it is being used in today&amp;rsquo;s tech ecosystemn* explore ways in which we can make ACS more efficientn* discuss some recent advancements in how ML can benefit datacenters from research community</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Proxies, TLS, and Injecting Security Into Cloud Communication</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1087.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1087.html</guid>
      <description>With the expansion of moving legacy applications into public clouds, there have been an increased need for features in proxies to inject security into legacy application deployments. In this talk, we present extensions made to the Apache Traffic Server proxy over the past two years to enable the secure deployment of legacy applications in a wider variety of network configurations. Specifically, we discuss how Traffic Sever can be used for Layer 4 Routing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-Service IoT Data Analytics with StreamPipes</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1077.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1077.html</guid>
      <description>In many application domains such as manufacturing, the integration and continuous processing of real-time sensor data from the Internet of Things (IoT) is crucial to continuously monitor and detect upcoming situations. While continuous processing of events in scalable architectures is already well supported by the existing Big Data tool landscape, building such applications requires technical effort and programming skills, which is often not present in manufacturing companies. To solve this problem, we have developed StreamPipes (https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Serving Clean URLs via Custom Internet Media Types on Tomcat</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1145.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1145.html</guid>
      <description>Increasingly static site generators are being used to create a presence on the web, both for the speed and simplicity of the resulting static pages. A related trend is the use of &amp;lsquo;clean&amp;rsquo; URLs with no resource name extensions, such as /products/mousetrap instead of /products/mousetrap.html. Clean URLs are more memorable, less fragile, do not leak implementation information, and are more search engine friendly. Because the default Tomcat implementation determines MIME type by filename extension, &amp;lsquo;clean&amp;rsquo; filenames are traditionally produced by servlet mapping or URL rewriting, perhaps coupled with Apache HTTP Server in front of Tomcat using mod_rewrite.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wire Encryption In HDFS: Protect Your Data From Others, Not Yourself</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1175.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 15:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1175.html</guid>
      <description>Wire data encryption is a key component of the Hadoop Distributed File System (HDFS). HDFS can enforce different levels of data protection, allowing users to specify one based on their own needs. However, such enforcement comes in as an all-or-nothing feature. Namely, wire encryption is enforced either for all accesses or none. Since encryption bears a considerable performance cost, the all-or-nothing condition forces users to choose between &amp;lsquo;faster but unencrypted&amp;rsquo; or &amp;lsquo;encrypted but slower&amp;rsquo; for all clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Hudi (Incubating) : the past, present and future of efficient data lake architectures</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1168.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1168.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Hudi is a newly incubating project at the ASF. Originally created at Uber, to power it’s vast big data lake, Hudi provides key features like atomic writes, snapshot isolation, incremental views, rollbacks, point-in-time restores, file size management &amp;amp; many more. To date, the big data community has been polarized amongst batch and streaming systems, when balancing data freshness and scale. Hudi also addresses a combined need for speed and scale, that does not naturally fit into existing batch and streaming data processing architectures, by way of ability to support continuous ingestion and asynchronous compaction of row &amp;amp; columnar data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Behind the Scenes of the Apache Software Foundation</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1090.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1090.html</guid>
      <description>This presentation will give you everything you always wanted to know about the Apache Software Foundation (ASF), but were afraid to ask. It will show you that there is more than just the Apache web server, and provide you with information on how the ASF works and its history. The difference between membership and committership, who decides what, how elections take place, the technical infrastructure, project management committees, and the philosophy behind the incubator.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customizing virtual machines with cloud init</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1009.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1009.html</guid>
      <description>This presentation will cover the basic design around how CloudStack implements support for cloud-init datasources, configuring the cloud-init service within a VM template to talk to one of the CloudStack supported datasources, and give a basic introduction to using cloud-init to customize virtual machines upon deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deploying a Java-based Tomcat application to Azure</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1159.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1159.html</guid>
      <description>In this talk, you will learn how you can use Azure Pipelines to deploy a Java web application to Apache Tomcat with a MySQL database on Azure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Step to Hybrid Cloud Computation: Elastic YARN and Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1174.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1174.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;In this presentation, we will introduce our work: Elastic YARN, which is an elastic, cloud-native solution and it allows co-location YARN and Kubernetes for both on-premises and on-cloud. Audiences can learn how to build a hybrid, low-cost and easy-to-use computation platform while ensuring the SLA by leveraging our work. Abstract Enterprise continues to evolve towards data-driven, more types of workloads will come onboard, the challenges of managing mixed workloads emerge. It&amp;rsquo;s essential to think about what is the most flexible architecture to manage batch jobs and long-running services both on-premises and on-cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How eBay build Data Quality Platform with Apache Griffin</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1030.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1030.html</guid>
      <description>High Quality data plays an important role for incubating awesome big data applications. In real projects, governing data, observing their quality health, and taking remedy actions are tedious and time-consuming. Apache Griffin is an open source Data Quality solution for Big Data, which supports both batch and streaming mode. It offers a unified process to measure your data quality from different perspectives, helping you build trusted data assets, therefore boost your confidence for your business.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IoT Applications and Patterns using Apache Spark &amp; Apache Bahir</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1085.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1085.html</guid>
      <description>The Internet of Things (IoT) is all about connected devices that produce and exchange data, and building applications that produce insights from these high volumes of data are very challenging and require an understanding of multiple protocols, platforms, and other components. On this session, we will start by providing a quick introduction to IoT, some of the common analytic patterns used on IoT, and also touch on the MQTT protocol and how it is used by IoT solutions some of the quality of services tradeoffs to be considered when building an IoT application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring of CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1053.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1053.html</guid>
      <description>Our approach of monitoring the CloudStack management server, parts of CloudStacks ecosystem and its underlying components. We give an introduction of how to monitor virtual routers, customer systems and customer resources in CloudStack.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panel discussion on recognizing non-code contributions</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1032.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1032.html</guid>
      <description>A discussion panel with 2 or 3 projects who have been successful at growing their communities outside the English speaking countries and how they did it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RocksDB Based Storage Engine Recent Improvements</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1128.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1128.html</guid>
      <description>In last year&amp;rsquo;s NGCC session &amp;lsquo;Cassandra Pluggable Storage Engine&amp;rsquo;, Instagram Cassandra team presented a new RocksDB based Cassandra storage engine which brings us huge performance win. Since then our team have been actively working on the new storage engine for adding missing features and further improving efficiency. In this session I will talk about our work on following sections and their impacts to our production system.n* Large disaggregated flash disk supportn* RocksDB based streaming improvementsn* Decoding improvementsn* Space amplification improvementsn* Some missing features added</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taming the Herd - Tuning ATS for linear video</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1114.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1114.html</guid>
      <description>At Comcast we have a unique challenge of serving both static and live linear content via our CDN. In general a thundering herd (multiple instantaneous simultaneous requests for the same content) is not a large concern for static files barring a few situations like serving automatic pushed update files. However when serving live content the nature of it means you are almost always generating a herd or on the verge of it due to timing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Backup and Recovery in CloudStack (it&#39;s Here!)</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1137.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1137.html</guid>
      <description>This presentation will demonstrate the long awaited Backup &amp;amp; Recovery Framework feature. The presentation will feature a real-world demonstration as well explain the design philosophy and how the feature has been built to be agnostic of the backend Backup and Recovery software in use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ceph with CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1134.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1134.html</guid>
      <description>In this presentation, we are going to give a brief introduction to Ceph and cover some considerations around it&amp;rsquo;s architecture, both in general and related to CloudStack. We are going to cover Ceph&amp;rsquo;s integration into CloudStack, compare it&amp;rsquo;s feature set versus other Primary Storage solutions for CloudStack and also share some general advises on it&amp;rsquo;s setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hatching the Clutch - A Guide to the Apache Incubator</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1113.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1113.html</guid>
      <description>What is the Apache Incubator? What is required from projects in order to graduate? What resources are available and which are required? What does the Foundation provide? Why is the dev email list so important? What about your Mentors? We are all volunteers and strive to be your gateway into taking full advantage of what the Foundation has to offer. Let&amp;rsquo;s review the state of the Clutch and see what is happening now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Encrypt Apache Tomcat</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1001.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1001.html</guid>
      <description>The Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt initiative has changed the landscape for online security. The capital cost of cryptographic security for every web site worldwide has been lowered from potentially thousands of dollars per year to zero. One of the trade-offs for the availability of these free certificates is that they are short-lived, making automated deployment of certificates an essential piece of any deployment plan. Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt supports Apache httpd out of the box for single-command renewal and deployment on a single host, while with Tomcat it&amp;rsquo;s more complicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Managing Hundreds of Petabytes of data in the Cloud</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1012.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1012.html</guid>
      <description>Twitter&amp;rsquo;s on premise HDFS clusters are scaled out to handle hundreds of petabyte data serving thousands of developers every day. Managing such large scale data introduces several challenges. Organization, discovery, data life cycle, replication, schema management and many more questions needs to be answered at scale. Our data infrastructure is built on different open source and in house projects working together to solve this problem. While we extend our data to cloud, we had to solve similar challenges on cloud environment at Twitter scale.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Next Generation Cassandra Compaction, Going beyond LCS</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1011.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1011.html</guid>
      <description>Cassandra users with general purpose workloads typically must choose the lesser of two evils between the default “write optimized” Size Tiered Compaction Strategy (STCS) and the “read optimized” Leveled Compaction Strategy (LCS). It is typical these days to hear “use LCS unless it explodes, in which case use STCS…unless that explodes, in which case you are out of luck”. I believe that by taking what we as a community learned from the development and real world deployment of LCS, we can create a next generation compaction strategy which offers all of the benefits of LCS with few of the drawbacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Observability in distributed system</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1129.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1129.html</guid>
      <description>Observability is quite important for the cloud native application. Itncould be a challenge if we build up the system observer from thenstrache. By leveraging the Skywalking&amp;rsquo;s extension mechanism, we couldnsend out the data to the backend directly to improve thenObservability of the Cloud Native Service. In distributed applications, horizontal sharding and transactio coordination are most popular solutions. Observability for businessninvocation on sharding scenario are not enough; but observer allnsharded details of backend infrastructures indifferently are tooncomplicated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimizing Big Data Pipelines with Apache Nemo (Incubating)</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1167.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1167.html</guid>
      <description>Optimizing scheduling and communication behaviors of big data pipelines for resource and data characteristics is crucial for achieving high performance. For example, optimizing for geographically-distributed resources, cheap transient resources, disk-based large data shuffle, and skewed data have recently received a lot of interest and attention. The new incubating Apache Nemo project aims to make it easy to express and enforce such optimizations by providing a policy interface that transforms an intermediate representation (IR) of data processing applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peeking Behind the Curtain: The Anatomy of a Real Major Incident</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1212.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1212.html</guid>
      <description>Failures are inevitable. But when they occur, our goal should be to resolve them as quickly and efficiently as possible. PagerDuty has developed an open-source Incident Response framework based on the Incident Command System (ICS). That product-independent process has helped many organizations set up Incident Response processes that resolve technical issues as quickly and effectively as possible. There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of documentation you can follow, but how do incidents actually play out in real-time when they happen?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Processing IoT Data from End to End with MQTT and Apache Kafka</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1107.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1107.html</guid>
      <description>This session discusses end-to-end use cases such as connected cars, smart home or healthcare sensors where you integrate IoT devices with enterprise IT using open source technologies and standards. MQTT is a lightweight messaging protocol for Internet of Things (IoT). However, MQTT is not built for high scalability, longer storage or easy integration to legacy systems. Apache Kafka is a highly scalable distributed streaming platform, which ingests, stores, processes and forwards high volumes of data from thousands of IoT devices.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Traffic Server Remap Update</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1064.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 12:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1064.html</guid>
      <description>Rewriting URLs, or &amp;lsquo;remapping&amp;rsquo;, is probably the single most used feature of the Traffic Servernproxy. With the transition to YAML from a proprietary line based format, it was decided to startnover with effectively a blank slate, to design a configuration with a functionality emphasizingnpower and flexibility over compatibility. This talk will elaborate on the decision path leading upnto this complete restructuring, the design of the configuration, and examples of its use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Cassandra community health</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1076.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1076.html</guid>
      <description>This talk will discuss the current health of the Apache Cassandra community looking at everything from community adoption, user adoption, health of contributors/committers, project velocity and a number of other measures of community health. In this talk Ben will also discuss broader market changes and challenges that impact the Apache Cassandra community drawn from our experience at Instaclustr, discussions with industry analysts and public data sources. This talk will be an update on the state of Apache Cassandra community presentation from NGCC 2017.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Iceberg: a table format for distributed databases</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1166.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1166.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;This talk will introduce Apache Iceberg (Incubating), a new table format designed for distributed databases that can be used directly by any size application. It will cover Iceberg’s design and the features that distinguish it from other table formats, including: -Reliable schema evolutio -Hidden partitioningn-Atomic operationsn-Support for object stores like S3n-Support for direct client access This talk will also present how Iceberg performs at scale in Netflix’s environment.&amp;rsquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache SkyWalking -- Top level open source APM</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1058.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1058.html</guid>
      <description>SkyWalking has just graduated as Top Level Project in this year. SkyWalking is an open source APM system, including monitoring, tracing, diagnosing capabilities for distributed systems in Cloud Native architecture. In the modern world, we have legacy and cloud-native distributed systems, even in hybrid. SkyWalking provides different observability methods, including language agents and service mesh angle, which adopt different scenarios. In this session, I will introduce what SkyWalking do, and how we do it, even without requiring any big data tech.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Netflix manages petabyte scale Apache Cassandra in the cloud</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1010.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1010.html</guid>
      <description>At Netflix, we manage petabytes of data in Apache Cassandra which must be reliably accessible to users in mere milliseconds. To achieve this, we have built sophisticated control planes that turn our persistence layer based on Apache Cassandra into a truly self-driving system. We will start with the user interface that Netflix developers use to interact with their Cassandra databases and dive deep into the automation that powers it all. From cluster creation, through scaling up, to cluster death, complex automation drives large fleets of virtual machines hosted on the AWS cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lessons learned while migrating 3000 openvz containers to CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1127.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1127.html</guid>
      <description>When Leaseweb acquired a new company 3000 public cloud customers we had to come up with a strategy to move all these VMs to our CloudStack setup. During this talk we will share: how we migrated a large foreign openvz environment into our kvm cloudstack environment in an automated fashion minimizing customer impact. The lessons we learned along the way and how we would do it again in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life beyond Kafka with Apache Pulsar</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1153.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1153.html</guid>
      <description>In a world where everything is connected, trillions of devices are sending data in real-time to data centers. Apache Kafka as a streaming platform is the system by excellence for many years. However, there are many competitors who are making its life more difficult. In this talk, I will introduce to one of them, Apache Pulsar sponsored by Yahoo itself. Pulsar is the next generation messaging system that uses a different architecture to achieve durability, performance, scalability, efficiency, multi-tenancy and geographic replication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of the cat, new and upcoming</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1035.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1035.html</guid>
      <description>This presentation will detail the current state of the Apache Tomcat project and its community. After going through information on recent releases, community metrics and security advisories, this will cover important new and upcoming features. This includes HTTP/X support, clustering, TLS, cloud enablement, and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Apache Way - Not only the What but the Why</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1056.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1056.html</guid>
      <description>The Apache Way consists of the basic core tenets, embraced by all ASF projects, which define how Open Source projects should be managed, governed and maintained. But in addition to a simply list of what those tenets are, we will dig deeper and discover the history and rationale behind them all. The incredible success of the Apache Way can be used to immediate advantage in your open source project and actual forms the core philosophy behind InnerSource.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The future of the CloudStack Virtual Router</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1157.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1157.html</guid>
      <description>This talk surveys and explores the scopes and design for the next-generation network model consolidation in CloudStack and a new super-fast micro-vm based VR. The talk will discuss the scope and goals for the next-generation VR, consolidation of basic and advanced networks and zones, flexible networking topologies, UI based network designing, a standard systemvm patching mechanism and uniform VR programming interface with a lightweight secured agent, faster rules programming and zero-downtime upgrades.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Apache Traffic Control to cache any web object at scale</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1002.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1002.html</guid>
      <description>This talk will focus on how any organization can deploy a Content Delivery Network (CDN) to cache web object at scale using Apache Traffic Control (ATC) and Apache Traffic Server (ATS). Topics covered will be a brief introduction to the projects, a high-level overview of traffic routing on a CDN, followed by a deep dive into how to efficiently cache objects on an ATC CDN using ATS. Based on years of experience operating ATC CDNs, several different scenarios with corresponding object types (video, web content, etc) will be presented.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>YuniKorn: A Universal Resource Scheduler for both YARN and Kubernetes</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1173.html</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2019 11:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1173.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;We will talk about our open source work - YuniKorn scheduler project (Y for YARN, K for K8s, uni- for Unified) brings long-wanted features such as hierarchical queues, fairness between users/jobs/queues, preemption to Kubernetes; and it brings service scheduling enhancements to YARN. Any improvements to this scheduler can benefit both Kubernetes and YARN community. Abstract: YARN schedulers are optimized for high-throughput, multi-tenant batch workloads. It can scale up to 50k nodes per cluster, and schedule 20k containers per second; On the other side, Kubernetes schedulers are optimized for long-running services, but many features like hierarchical queues, fairness resource sharing, and preemption etc, are either missing or not mature enough at this point of time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluating Content/Text Extraction at Scale with Apache Tika</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1072.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1072.html</guid>
      <description>Text extraction tools are essential for obtaining the textual content and metadata of computer files for use in a wide variety of applications, including search and natural language processing tools. Techniques and tools for evaluating text extraction tools are largely missing from academia and industry. This talk will focus on recent improvements to Apache Tika&amp;rsquo;s tika-eval module to help integrators evaluate content extraction at scale. The tika-eval module was initially developed for a single batch mode on a single vm.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Visibility in Hybrid and Multi Clouds</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1037.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1037.html</guid>
      <description>Network Visibility in Apache CloudStack</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realtime Geospatial Analytics with GPUs, RAPIDS, and Apache Arrow</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1165.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1165.html</guid>
      <description>Prior to RAPIDS, geospatial analytics, especially networking analytics for routing, required large CPU clusters to process. Even with 100s of machines, it would take hours if not days to get answers. With RAPIDS, and Apache 2.0 open source project built on Apache Arrow, graph analytics, clustering, and many other geospatial workflows can be completed end to end in seconds. Learn how to load data (CSV, Parquet, or ORC) directly into GPU memory with cuIO, process it with Dask-cuDF, and analyze it with cuML and cuGraph in seconds, all on a single node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>There&#39;s life in the (old) dog yet: Apache Edgent reinvents itself and Edge Analytics</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1016.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1016.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Edgent (formerly Quarks) is a Project in the Apache Incubator since early 2016. The main focus of the project is to simplify edge processing pipelines. Through the last year it went a bit silent around the project and although the topic is hotter than ever the project lost its drive and went into hibernation. With the rise of other projects in the (industrial) IoT ecosystem like Apache PLC4X and Apache IoTDB there are a lot of new use cases and applications for edge processing, especially in the field of industrial IoT thus, a group of contributors from other IoT related projects has gathered to bring the project back to life and on track.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Getting Apache Traffic Control Up And Running</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1046.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 17:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1046.html</guid>
      <description>CDN-in-a-Box is a subproject within Apache Traffic Control (ATC) to build a test/experimental CDN in docker on an individual workstation. The process is still challenging, so I&amp;rsquo;d like to do a workshop to guide interested users through the process on their own laptops. The goal is to show them how the CDN works at a fairly low level and how to test that the various parts work as expected as well as troubleshooting if things go awry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Mile in My Shoes: How Empathy &amp; Compassion Can Transform Your Work &amp; Your Life</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1200.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1200.html</guid>
      <description>In many places, we&amp;rsquo;re told to &amp;lsquo;leave our emotions out of it,&amp;rsquo; in our work, and in our other technical endeavors, including in open source communities. But that is an irrational, dangerously naïve point of view, one that often leads us to not concern ourselves with the feelings of others, thereby allowing biases (intended or not) to come into play. This harms our communities, by excluding valuable contributors, and their skills and ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudstack API development 101</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1039.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1039.html</guid>
      <description>This is a primer to getting started with adding functionality to CloudStack. In this presentation we will go over a custom Maven archetype that will fast track CloudStack development, whether the goal is to develop functionality to contribute to CloudStack project or to integrate CloudStack with site specific systems. It is geared toward Java developers who are new to the CloudStack code base.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customer Cloud Portal</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1162.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1162.html</guid>
      <description>A technical overview showing how we at itelligence as a cloud service provider use CloudStack and how we extent our infrastructure with additional service components to enhance our cloud service portfolio.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GeoSpatial and Temporal Forecasting in Uber Marketplace</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1061.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1061.html</guid>
      <description>Uber’s Marketplace is the algorithmic brain and decision engine behind our ride-sharing services. Marketplace Forecasting builds and deploys ML algorithms to handle the immense coordination, hyperlocal decision making, and learning needed to tackle the enormous scale and movement of our transportation network. In order for our decision engines to be future-aware, we need to be able to “see into the future” as accurately as possible across both space and time. In Uber, we use H3 (a hexagonal hierarchical geospatial indexing system) to partition the data geospatially.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning and Data Analytics in the Content Delivery Context</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1063.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1063.html</guid>
      <description>In line with the content delivery community&amp;rsquo;s interest in data-driven operational insights and improving operational efficiency, this presentation and discussion will address the following topics: (1) What are Machine Learning, Deep Learning, and the different types of analytics (from descriptive through prescriptive)? (2) What are the potential benefits and risks of analytical solutions? (3) And finally - a walkthrough of some example use cases from modern content delivery networks and their corresponding analytical solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The First Mile -- Edge and IoT Data Collection with Apache NiFi and MiNiFi</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1118.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1118.html</guid>
      <description>Apache NiFi provided a revolutionary data flow management system with a broad range of integrations with existing data production, consumption, and analysis ecosystems, all covered with robust data delivery and provenance infrastructure. Now learn about the follow-on project which expands the reach of NiFi to the edge, Apache MiNiFi. MiNiFi is a lightweight application which can be deployed on hardware orders of magnitude smaller and less powerful than the existing standard data collection platforms.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Anycast ATC Integration at Comcast</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1047.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1047.html</guid>
      <description>Anycast is an industry proven technology and is quickly becoming a requirement for off-the-shelf CDNs as well as CDN-as-a-Service. In this talk we will investigate how Comcast is integrating anycast functionality into Apache Traffic Control to improve resiliency, convergence and localization.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cloudstack Locking Service</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/3001.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/3001.html</guid>
      <description>As CloudStack cannot work with any mysql clustering solution, it is time to explore a new locking service, manager and pluggable interface which would allow CloudStack DB to be HA enabled with multi-master read/write. Talk will focus on, - Need for a locking service and challenges with existing CloudStack architecture - Different possible clustering solution that can be adopted - Showcasing a PoC for future implementation with minimal changes to existing architecture using percona xtradb or any other clustering solution - Additionally, explore the idea of getting rid of mshost table, and use locking service to find about other management servers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Indexing and Search at Scale with Apache Lucene</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1000.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1000.html</guid>
      <description>Come have a look under the covers at new data structures that enable geospatial and multi-dimensional indexing and search at massive scale in Apache Lucene. This talk will cover the indexing structures considered and ultimately implemented in the Apache Lucene Open Source Project along with the 25 - 30X boost in performance and centimeter spatial accuracy achieved in the latest release. Join us and see what&amp;rsquo;s next for scalable Geospatial Search in Apache Lucene.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Going Beyond StringUtils: A Broader Look at Apache Commons</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1152.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1152.html</guid>
      <description>The Apache Commons Project is home to one of the more widely consumed Java utility functions, namely “StringUtils.isBlank(String str);”. But when you look beyond commons-lang, you’ll find a wide array of heavily utilized and extremely useful tools. For example, commons-cli is the command line parser used by the Apache Maven project; commons-fileupload is heavily used by both Apache Tomcat and Apache Struts; commons-text is heavily used by Apache Hadoop; and commons-dbcp is a database connection pool used across Tomcat as well as the Spring Framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Storage in Cloudstack</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1100.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1100.html</guid>
      <description>With the increased focus and legislation around data sovereignty requirements, storage solutions play an increasingly important role in cloud infrastructures. We will present an overview of the evolution of storage orchestration in Apache CloudStack, with a focus on managed storage. It will also shed light on some upcoming features and the future direction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using Apache Pulsar to Provide Real-Time IoT Analytics on the Edge</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1015.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 15:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1015.html</guid>
      <description>he business value of data decreases rapidly after it is created, particularly in use cases such as fraud prevention, cybersecurity, and real-time system monitoring. The high-volume, high-velocity datasets used to feed these use cases often contain valuable, but perishable, insights that must be acted upon immediately. In order to maximize the value of their data enterprises must fundamentally change their approach to processing real-time data to focusing reducing their decision latency on the perishable insights that exist within their real-time data streams.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Commons State of the Union</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1154.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1154.html</guid>
      <description>We will go over the state of the Apache Commons Project. Where things stand, and will take a look at the future road map for the project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GeoMesa on top of Accumulo, HBase, Cassandra, and big data file formats for massive geospatial data - a LocationTech Project</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1164.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1164.html</guid>
      <description>LocationTech is the geospatial software working group of the Eclipse Foundation. The projects range from fundamental libraries that provide spatial operations to complex library suites which coordinate multiple Apache projects to build complete spatial processing solutions.nLocationTech GeoMesa builds on top of distributed Apache databases like Accumulo, HBase, Cassandra and Kafka to provide indexing, querying, and analysis for large spatio-temporal datasets. GeoMesa does this by integrating other LocationTech projects like JTS, Spatial4J, and SFCurve with these databases as well as Apache open source file formats such as Avro, Arrow, Orc, and Parquet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Encrypt Apache Traffic Control</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1198.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1198.html</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt is a free, automated certificate authority (CA) which is open for use to anyone who owns a domain name. Using Traffic Router as the DNS, we have integrated with Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt when utilizing HTTPS on the delivery service domains. Many open source projects provide libraries to ease implementation of Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt, and for this project we used go-acme/lego (MIT licensed) to integrate with the Traffic Ops Golang API. Integration with Let&amp;rsquo;s Encrypt provides many advantages including saving money by using a completely free CA, saving time with automation including certificate renewal, and improving reliability by eliminating manual intervention for certificate generation and deployment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open vSwitch with DPDK on CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1040.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1040.html</guid>
      <description>Support for Open vSwitch with DPDK has been introduced on CloudStack version 4.12. In this talk we will go through the motivations and advantages of using DPDK on KVM hosts, high level architecture of the feature, what is needed and how can it be used on production environments and future works.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Troubleshooting the Virtual Router - Run and Get Diagnostics</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1098.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1098.html</guid>
      <description>Demonstration of CloudStack’s latest features for troubleshooting the Virtual Router connectivity and configuration, called Run and Get Diagnostics. Run Diagnostics gives the admin ability to execute diagnostics commands native the VR OS directly from the CloudStack UI. Admin is able to determine connectivity capabilities of the VR without logging into the SystemVM at all. Get diagnostics feature allow the admin to gather information about the SystemVM as fast as clicking on a button in the ‘QuickView’ of the VM.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using PLC4X and LF Edge EVE to build a next generation Industry 4.0 IoT Platform</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1131.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1131.html</guid>
      <description>Industrial IoT platforms are undergoing rapid shift away from vertically integrated systems built mostly out of embedded software towards an Edge Virtualization Platforms and commodity, cloud native software. While the cloud, big-data, fast-data, machine-learning has been a huge thing in the IT industry for the last years, the production industry was stuck in a proprietary world, dominated by some of the big players. Two open source projects now offer the building blocks for the new platform that can hope to break that proprietary chokehold.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Science Data Analytics Platform (SDAP)</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1163.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1163.html</guid>
      <description>An Analytics Center Framework (ACF) is an environment that enables the confluence of resources for scientific investigation. It harmonizes data, tools and computational resources which subsequently enable the research community to focus on the investigation. The Earth science community is an innovative community. We produce many tools and solutions to improve how we do science. In computer science, a framework is a reusable, semi-complete application that can be specialized to produce custom applications [Johnson:88].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Apache Traffic Control Environment Deployments with Ansible</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1062.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1062.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Traffic Control is a set of applications designed to complement Apache Traffic Server to comprise a Content Delivery Network. Currently the creation of a complete production-ready CDN environment is a complex process. I will be demonstrating automation leveraging Ansible and CDN environment designs to facilitate consistent and more rapid testing environment creation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Building a smart query mediation engine for Genome Research using Apache Drill</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1051.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1051.html</guid>
      <description>The integration of both clinical and genomics data into a single platformnthat will allow the researchers to search, analyze and discover the hidde patterns in biomedical databases. Developing this integrated platform be-ncomes a complex and challenging task due to (i) heterogeneous data typesn(ii) huge volume of data (iii) number of attributes are di erent across thendata (iv) generated data are from heterogeneous platform and (v) corre-nlation between clinical and genomics data are di erent to each other andn(vi) scalability factors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Episode IV - A New Hope: Industry 4.0 done our way</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1079.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1079.html</guid>
      <description>It is a period of technological change. Rebel Industry 4.0 open-source software solutions, striking from hidden bases, have won their first victories against the evil proprietary Industrial Empire. During the battle, Rebel spies managed to implement industrial protocols to the Empire’s ultimate weapons, the industrial Programmable Logic Controllers, almost unprotected pieces of hardware with enough power to destroy an entire planet. Pursued by the Empire’s sinister agents, a representative of the project races to Las Vegas aboard his intercontinental sub-orbital shuttle, custodian of his plans to revolutionize the way we are building Industry 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NoVNC console implementation in CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1109.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1109.html</guid>
      <description>NoVNC is an open-source browser based VNC client, implemented using HTML5 technologies (Web Sockets, Canvas) with encryption (wss://) support. Proposed NoVNC implementation provides better performance and is more responsive when compared to the current ajax-based console in Apache CloudStack. Our implementation is based on NoVNC and websockify. Websockify is a websocket proxy converting WebSocket request from browser to TCP request and then forward it to VNC server. We have already implemented a NoVNC console for CloudStack 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Openstack from a CloudStack perspective</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1097.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 11:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1097.html</guid>
      <description>An experienced CloudStack developer will show his journey to deploy an OpenStack cloud. We will compare the pros and cons of CloudStack and OpenStack from the following perspectives:n(i) Deployment: cost, time and risks of deploying a CloudStack vs OpenStack infrastructure;n(ii) Maintenance: the costs and time required on maintaining a Cloud orchestrated with CloudStack and another with OpenStack; and,n(ii) Development: how development on both orchestrators is done? What looks like the codebase of each project and which technologies are involved?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Apache Mynewt - ASF&#39;s Embedded OS Project</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1105.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1105.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Mynewt is an operating system for low powered embedded systems based on 32-bit microcontrollers. At the core, it is a small pre-emptive RTOS and an extensive set of modules for connectivity, file systems, power and performance management options and lots more. It is a highly flexible, responsive, general purpose OS for constrained devices, think of it as embedded Linux for devices that can’t run Linux. Features include a secure bootloader, image management, hardware abstraction, instrumentation for stats and logs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Automating Apache Traffic Control Server Deployments with IPv6</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1020.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1020.html</guid>
      <description>Apache Traffic Control has some built-in tools for assisting in the installation and deployment of new servers; however, it is still a somewhat manual and repetitive process. I will be demonstrating how the Traffic Control API, used in conjunction with IPv6 autoconf can be used to streamline the deployment process, allowing servers to configure themselves post-install. Will highlight the use of the ‘tc-netconfig’ application, which was developed to facilitate this process.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Customized CloudStack in Leaseweb</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1161.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1161.html</guid>
      <description>In this talk we will share how Leaseweb customized the CloudStack project to serve our business model and our customers, by doing some improvements and do some bug fixes. We always focused on upgrading our fork to the latest in the community while making sure all our improvements are ported to the latest version. In this talk we will tell you about some features and fixes we did like: - multiple NICs feature, - NoVNC, autoscaling, - SSL offloading in load balancer - and other changes made to serve some of our customers&#39; needs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Data Management in Apache Spark</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1117.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1117.html</guid>
      <description>The volume of spatial data increases at a staggering rate. This talk comprehensively studies how existing works, such as GeoSpark, extend Apache Spark to uphold massive-scale spatial data. During this talk, we first provide a background introduction of the characteristics of spatial data and the history of distributed data management systems. A follow-up section presents the common approaches used by the practitioners to extend Spark and introduces the vital components in a generic spatial data management system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java &#43; Serverless - Finally a match made in Heaven?</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1214.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1214.html</guid>
      <description>Why isn’t Java a more popular language for serverless developers? How does Apache Openwhisk work with Java? Despite there being 10 million Java developers, Java is being used for only 6% of serverless workloads according to a recent survey. Historical problems with long cold-starts, heavy-weight frameworks and lack of tooling have made Java an unpopular choice for serverless development…. until now! In this session, I will take you on a journey to explain what has changed with Java to finally make it an amazing language for building serverless applications, using the open source Apache Openwhisk platform!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modern UI for CloudStack</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1143.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1143.html</guid>
      <description>The CloudStack UI code has tolerated massive technical debt over the years and the UI codebase has reached a breaking point. In this talk, we will do a comparison of modern UI development techniques, the pros and cons of current UI UX and codebase, ideas and experiments of a new UI for CloudStack. We need to discuss and propose a new UI that:n* Has CloudMonkey like api discovery and show/hide/block, buttons/sections based on what is allowedn* URL router to navigate to resources, and clicking back button does not close the UIn* Easy to maintain, implement and extend via plugins etc.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>From (Single) ISP-CDN - To Multi-ISP CDN</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1197.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1197.html</guid>
      <description>&amp;lsquo;Traffic-control was built as an ISP CDN, serving content within a single ISP. Using traffic-control for creating a multi-ISP CDN, puts up challenges in various aspects: starting from the deployment of the different TC components outside of the ISPs, towards the isolation between different ISPs, as well as self-service, dealing simultaneously with different structures of ISP networks, the changing popularity of content in different ISP etc. In this session we would like to described few of the above challenges, as well as the derived traffic-control components requirements, flexibility and modularity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Geospatial Data and Processing - Reusable Building Blocks</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1150.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1150.html</guid>
      <description>Reuse of common elements for geospatial information and processing results in increased productivity, lower interoperability friction, and higher data quality. This presentation provides a survey of reusable geospatial building blocks. Common practices for coordinate reference systems (CRSs), spatial geometries and data arrays used for projects with geospatial content will be described based on open source projects and open standards. Emphasis is placed on the use of open standards including the recently updated OGC CRS Well Known Text (CRS WKT) and OGC APIs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Become an IoT Developer (and Have Fun!)</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1120.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1120.html</guid>
      <description>I started off my life as a developer writing machine code and C and working on some low-level hardware projects. Then this thing called the internet come along and I moved into the web application space for a couple of decades. More recently I&amp;rsquo;ve moved back into commercial IoT development and not unexpectedly a lot has changed over that time. In this talk, I&amp;rsquo;ll cover what it&amp;rsquo;s like developing IoT projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Features of Apache RocketMQ</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1213.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1213.html</guid>
      <description>In the past year, Apache RocketMQ has released a series of new features including transactional messages, ACLs, message track, multiple replicas storage, and multi-language clients. These features are all from contributors from many companies. nThis talk is not only about bringing technical analysis related to these new features, but also will share how to collaborate on the development of important features in the community, which is very important for Apache.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Cloudstack Collaboration Conference</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1112.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 09:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1112.html</guid>
      <description>The CloudStack Project VP welcomes delegates to the CloudStack Collaboration Conference. And gives opening remarks about the CloudStack community, with special guest joining on stage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Content Delivery Track</title>
      <link>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1045.html</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://elek.github.io/acah2021/sessions/1045.html</guid>
      <description>This presentation will open the track and serve as a welcome to those attending. I will cover what’s new in the ATC (Apache Traffic Control) community, introduce our new committers and PMC members, talk about what we will cover during the conference and then talk a little about the CDN market as a whole.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
